(1858年）
（美国内战的二年前）
（德州的某处）
谁在黑暗中鬼鬼祟祟的？
Who's that stumblin' around in the dark?
报上你的目的，否则准备断臂
State your business or prepare to get winged!
冷静，两位 我没有恶意
Calm yourselves, gentlemen. I mean you no harm.
我只是同样疲倦的旅人
I'm simply a fellow weary traveler.
停,马儿
Boy.
寒冷的清晨，两位
Good cold evening, gentlemen.
我在找一对奴隶商名叫史佩克兄弟
I'm looking for a pair of slave traders that go by the name of the Speck Brothers.
是你们吗？
Might that be you?
- 谁想知道？ - 我想
- Who wants to know? - Well, I do.
我是金史华兹医生 这是我的马费兹
I'm Dr. King Schultz. This is my horse, Fritz.
- 哪门子医生？ - 牙医
- What kinda doctor? - Dentist.
你们是史佩克兄弟吗？
Now, are you the Speck Brothers?
你们在格林维尔奴隶拍卖会中 买下那群人吗？
And did you purchase those men at the Greenville slave auction?
- 那又怎样？ - 我希望跟你们谈判
- So what? - So I wish to parley with you.
说英语
- Speak English.
抱歉
- Oh, I'm sorry.
请见谅，英语是我的第二语言
Please forgive me. It is a second language.
在你的财产中，我打听到…
Now, amongst your inventory, I've been led to believe,
有个我急欲获得的黑奴
is a specimen I'm keen to acquire.
各位可怜鬼好！
Hello, you poor devils!
你们有人是来自…
Is there one amongst you who was formerly a resident
卡洛肯庄园吗？
of the Carrucan plantation?
我来自卡洛肯庄园
I'm from the Carrucan plantation.
谁在说话？
Who said that?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
决哥
Django.
那你正是我在找的人
Then you are exactly the one I'm looking for.
你知道毕氏兄弟是谁吗？
Do you know who the Brittle Brothers are?
他们是谁？
Who are they?
大约翰
Big John.
艾利斯
Ellis.
罗杰
Roger.
有时他们叫他小拉杰
Sometime they call him Lil Raj.
他们是卡洛肯庄园的监工
They was overseers at the Carrucan plantation.
不再是了
Not anymore.
告诉我 如果再看到他们三人
Tell me... if you were to see any of these three gentlemen again,
- 你能认出吗？ - 喂
- would you recognize them? - Hey.
- 别那样跟他说话 - 怎样？
- Stop talkin' to him like that. - Like What?
那样
Like that.
老兄，我只是想确定…
My good man, I'm simply trying to ascertain...
说英语，可恶
Speak English, goddamn it.
大家冷静
Everybody calm down.
我只是想做生意的顾客
I'm simply a customer trying to conduct a transaction.
我不在乎，不卖，快滚
I don't care. No sale. Now, off with ya.
别傻了，他们就是要卖的
Don't be ridiculous. Of course they're for sale.
走开
Move it.
老兄，你只是想来个下马威
My good man, did you simply get carried away with your dramatic gesture
或是你把枪指着我有杀人意图？
or are you pointing your weapon at me with lethal intention?
最后机会，臭屁鬼
Last chance, fancy pants.
很好
Oh, very well.
抱歉杀了你的马 但我怕你乱来
I'm sorry to put a bullet in your beast, but I didn't want you to do anything rash
忘了先冷静下来
before you had a moment to come to your senses.
你这混帐王八蛋！
You goddamn son of a bitch!
你杀了罗斯柯
- You shot Roscoe! -
是啊
Well...
也杀了艾斯
And you killed Ace!
谁叫他威胁射杀我
I only shot your brother once he threatened to shoot me.
我相信我有…
And I do believe I have...
一、二、三、四
one, two, three, four...
五位证人能作证
five witnesses who can attest to that fact.
- 干，我的腿断了 - 废话
- Damn leg's busted! - No doubt.
拜托你别哭了
Now, if you could keep your caterwauling down to a minimum,
我想向决哥小伙子问完话
I'd like to finish my line of inquiry with young Django.
痛死了！
- God-fuckin'-damn it!
如我所说
- As I was saying...
如果再看到他们三人 你能认出吗？
if you were to see the Brittle Brothers again, you could recognize 'em?
可以
Yeah.
成交！
Sold American!
怎样，史佩克先生？
So, Mr. Speck? Mr. Speck?
史佩克先生？决哥小伙子卖多少？
How much for young Django here?
这铁链太夭寿了
That iron is nasty business.
拿一下好吗？
Oh, could you hold this for a moment?
谢谢
Thank you. Django?
决哥，你骑那只马
Get up on that horse.
还有，换作是我
Also, if I were you,
我会拿走史佩克大哥遗留的外套
I'd take that winter coat the dear departed Speck left behind.
黑鬼！不准碰我哥的外套
Nigger! Don't you touch my brother's coat.
该死
Goddamn it!
100元、10元…
One hundred... ten...
20元…
20...
再5元
and five...
买决哥小伙子
for young Django here.
既然他用不着了
And since he won't be needing it anymore,
我想买你哥的马
I'd like to purchase your brother's nag.
还有，史佩克先生
Also, Mr. Speck,
恐怕我需要收据，你有吗？
I'm afraid I will require a bill of sale. Do you have one?
去死吧，牙医
You go to hell, dentist.
就知道你没有
I thought not.
放心啦，我有备而来
No worries. I come prepared.
谢谢
Thank you.
这能充当收据
This will serve nicely as a bill of sale.
至于你们这些可怜鬼
Now, as to you poor devils.
依我看
So, as I see it,
谈到诸位的下一步
when it comes to the subject of what to do next,
你们有两个选择
you gentlemen have two choices.
第一选择
One:
我离开后 你们能扛着还没死的史佩克
Once I'm gone, you could lift that beast off the remaining Speck,
送他到最近的城镇
then carry him to the nearest town.
起码距离这里37英里
Which would be at least 37 miles back the way you came.
或是第二选择
Or two:
你们自行解开铁链
You could unshackle yourselves,
拿着那支枪
take that rifle,
轰了他的头，把两人给埋了
put a bullet in his head, bury the two of them deep,
去国内比较开化的地区
and then make your way to a more enlightened area of this country.
由你们选择
Choice is yours.
给个提示 要是你们有人热中天文学
Oh, and on the off chance there are any astronomy aficionados amongst you,
北极星是那颗
the North Star is that one.
拜拜
大伙儿，等一下，有话好说
Now wait a minute, fellas. Let's talk about this!
这种情况要讲道理
You gotta be reasonable in a situation like this!
我不是坏人，我只是做分内事
I'm not a bad guy. I'm just doin' my job!
蓝莓，我不是把吃剩的苹果给你？
Blueberry, didn't I give you my last apple?
这样吧
Tell you what, boys:
带我去艾尔帕索看医生 我会放你们自由
Take me to the doc in El Paso, I'll get you your freedom.
不要，拜托
No. No, please...
（道崔镇，德州）
听着
All right, now.
今晚吃两颗
I'd like you to take two of these tonight...
隔天早上就…
and then in the morning...
黑鬼在骑马
That's a nigger on a horse.
大家在看什么？
What's everybody staring at?
他们从没看过黑人骑马
They ain't never seen no nigger on a horse before.
早安，客栈老板
Good morning, innkeeper!
两杯啤酒给两位累坏的旅客
Two beers for two weary travelers.
还太早，再一小时才营业
It's still a bit early. We won't be open for another hour.
到时会提供早餐
By then, we'll be servin' breakfast.
你竟敢进来
What the hell you think you're doing, boy?
叫那黑鬼出去
Get that nigger outta here!
救命！救命！ 客栈老板
- Help! Help! - Innkeeper!
记得，叫警长来，不是治安官
Remember, get the sheriff, not the marshal.
警长！救命！
Sheriff! Help!
真扫兴
Alas.
我们只能自己倒酒了
Now we must act as our own bartender.
坐下，老弟
Sit down, my boy.
你是哪门子牙医？
What kind of dentist are you?
即便有马车，我有五年没行医了
Despite that cart, I haven't practiced dentistry in five years.
但最近我转行了
But these days, I practice a new profession...
赏金猎人
bounty hunter.
知道什么是赏金猎人吗？
Do you know what a bounty hunter is?
不明白
No.
就是…
Well...
奴隶交易是用人命换现金
the way the slave trade deals in human lives for cash,
赏金猎人是尸体换现金
a bounty hunter deals in corpses.
帽子
Hat
干杯
Prost.
州政府悬赏一个人头
The state places a bounty on a man's head.
我追踪那个人，找到就杀了他
I track that man, I find that man, I kill that man.
然后再把尸体运回当局
After I've killed him, I transport that man's corpse back to the authorities.
有时说来容易做起来难
Sometimes that's easier said than done.
我给当局尸体证明我确实杀了他
I show that corpse to the authorities, proving yes, indeed, I truly have killed him,
这时当局就会付我赏金
at which point the authorities pay me the bounty.
类似奴隶制，这一行是尸肉换现金
So, like slavery, it's a flesh for cash business.
什么是赏金？
What's a bounty?
像是酬金
It's like a reward.
你杀人？还有钱领？
You kill people? And they give you a reward?
杀特定对象，对
Certain people, yeah.
坏人
Bad people?
愈坏酬金愈高
Badder they are, bigger the reward.
所以我才找上你
Which brings me to you.
我得承认找你，是有点为难
And I must admit, I'm at a bit of a quandary when it comes to you.
一来我鄙视奴隶制度
On one hand, I despise slavery.
但另一方面我还是需要你帮忙
On the other hand, I need your help.
如果你无法拒绝，更好
If you're not in a position to refuse, all the better.
暂时我得借助你的力量来帮我
So, for the time being, I'm gonna make this slavery malarkey work to my benefit.
尽管如此
Still, having said that,
我感到内疚
I feel guilty.
所以我想要我俩达成协议
So, I would like the two of us to enter into an agreement.
我要找到毕氏兄弟
I'm looking for the Brittle Brothers.
不过这任务对我来说有个小麻烦
However, at this endeavor,
就是我不认得他们的长相
I'm at a slight disadvantage insofar as I don't know what they look like.
但你认得，对吧？
But you do. Don't ya?
我当然认得他们的长相
I know what they look like all right.
很好
Good.
我的提案如下
So here's my agreement.
你跟我同行直到找到他们
- You travel with me until we find them.
我们要去哪里？
- Where we goin'?
听说他们至少有两人 在北边的盖特林堡当监工
I hear at least two of them are overseeing up in Gatlinburg,
但我不知道位置
but I don't know where.
那表示得跑遍盖特林堡的庄园 直到找到他们
That means we visit every plantation in Gatlinburg till we find 'em.
找到他们时
And when we find them,
你指出他们，我杀掉他们
you point them out, and I kill them.
你愿意的话
You do that,
我同意放你自由 外加每个毕氏兄弟给25元 总共是75元
I agree to give you your freedom, $25 per Brittle Brother. That's $75.
真准时，警长来了
And, as if on cue, here comes the sheriff.
好，两位，闹够了
OK, boys. Fun's over.
出来
Come on out.
好，乡民，冷静
All right, folks, calm down.
去忙自己的事
Go about your business.
这些小丑很快会滚蛋
These jokers will be gone soon.
你们为什么来我的镇惹麻烦？
Now, why y'all wanna come into my town and start trouble?
吓坏了这群好人
And scare all these nice people.
你们没事可干
You ain't got nothing better to do
只会来比尔夏普的镇
than to come into Bill Sharp's town
胡搞一通？
and show your ass?
你竟然对警长开枪
What'd you just do to our sheriff?
现在能找治安官了
Now you can get the marshal.
治安官！治安官！
Marshal! Marshal!
- 要进去等吗？ - 能闪人吗？
- Should we wait inside? - Can we just leave?
你先请
After you.
把马车移到酒馆对街远一点
Move that buckboard a long ways across the street from the saloon.
我要六名枪手在后面
I want six men, six rifles behind it.
两名枪手在这边屋顶
I want two men, two rifles up on this roof.
两名枪手在那边屋顶
Two men, two rifles on that roof.
所有枪都瞄准前门
All the barrels aimed at that front door.
来人把可怜的比尔拖走
Somebody get poor Bill outta the goddamn street.
酒馆里的家伙！
You in the saloon!
我们有一百名枪手 在各个角落瞄准那间店
We got a hundred rifles aimed at every way out of that buildin'.
你们只有一个机会能活着出来
You got one chance to get out of this alive.
你和黑鬼立刻手举高出来 立刻照办
You and your nigger come out right now with your hands over your head, and I mean right now.
这位是我有幸谈话的治安官吗？
Is this the marshal I have the pleasure of addressing?
没错
Yes, it is.
我是美国治安官吉尔塔图
This is U.S. Marshal Gill Tatum.
太棒了，治安官
Na wunderbar, marshal.
我完全缴械了
I have relieved myself of all weapons,
如你所指示
and just as you have instructed,
我准备走出去
I am ready to step outside
手举高
with my hands raised above my head.
我相信这位…
I trust as a representative
美国刑法制度的代表
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America,
不会当街射杀我
I shan't be shot down in the street
无论是你或你的手下
by either you or your deputies
除非我受到司法审判
before I've had my day in court.
你指像你对警长干的事？
You mean like you did our sheriff.
像杀狗一样当街射杀他
Shot him down like a dog in the street.
对，就是这个意思
Yes, that's exactly what I mean.
身为执法者，你能保证…
Do I have your word as a lawman not to
不会像杀狗一样当街射杀我？
shoot me down like a dog in the street?
虽然我们都乐于看到这一幕
Well, much as we'd all enjoy seeing something like that,
但我的镇没人会动用私刑
ain't nobody gonna cheat the hangman in my town.
很好，治安官，我们要出去了
Fair enough, marshal. Here we come.
外头情况有点紧张
They're a little tense out there.
别轻举妄动，让我来谈判
So don't make any quick movements, and let me do the talking.
过来
Come ahead.
- 你没有武器？ - 没有
You unarmed? Yes, indeed we are.
塔图治安官，容我跟你和你手下…
Marshal Tatum, may I address you and your deputies,
还有所有道崔镇民…
and apparently the entire town of Daughtrey,
解释刚才的事件
as to the incident that just occurred?
继续
- Go on. - Thank you.
我叫做金史华兹医生
My name is Dr. King Schultz.
跟你一样，治安官 我也是执法人员
Like yourself, marshal, I'm a servant of the court.
死在污泥里的那个男人
The man lying dead in the dirt, who the good people of Daughtrey
道崔镇的好乡民选出的警长 自称比尔夏普的那个人
saw fit to elect as their sheriff, who went by the name of Bill Sharp,
其实是名为威拉佩克的通缉要犯
is actually a wanted outlaw by the name of Willard Peck,
他的人头值200元
with a price on his head of $200.
无论生死都是200元
Now that's $200, dead or alive.
鬼扯蛋
The hell, you say!
我明白这也许是不堪的消息
I'm aware this is probably disconcerting news.
但我愿意打赌…
But I'm willing to wager this man was elected sheriff
他在约两年前选上警长？
sometime in the past two years?
- 对 - 我知道是因为三年前…
Yeah. I know this because three years ago, he was rustling cattle
他偷了德州寇瑞根畜牧公司的牛
from the B.C. Corrigan Cattle Company of Lubbock, Texas.
这是通缉令
Now, this is a warrant
由德州奥斯汀巡回审判法官
made out by Circuit Court Judge Henry Allen
亨利艾伦罗德米克签署
Laudermilk of Austin, Texas.
你大可发电报问他
You're encouraged to wire him.
他会确认我的身分
He'll back up who I am and
以及你们已故警长的身分
who your dear departed sheriff was.
换句话说，治安官
In other words, marshal,
你欠我200元
you owe me $200.
要死啦
I'll be damned.
毕氏的任务完成后
After this Brittle business is behind us,
你就是自由民了
you'll be a free man,
有马，口袋里有75元
with a horse, $75 in your back pocket...
之后你有什么计划？
What's your plan after that?
找到我妻子
Find my wife,
买下她的自由之身
and buy her freedom.
决哥
Django,
没想到你是已婚男人
I had no idea you were a married man.
多数奴隶相信婚姻吗？
Do most slaves believe in marriage?
我和我妻子相信
Oh, me and my wife do.
卡洛肯大佬不相信 所以我们才逃走
Old Man Carrucan didn't. That's why we... we run off.
决哥
Django.
决哥，决哥
Django, Django-
你很有种，决哥
You got sand, Django.
这小子很有种
Boy's got sand.
我用不着有种的黑鬼
I got no use for a nigger with sand.
在他脸上烙了逃跑的“R”字
I want you to burn a runaway "r" right here on his cheek.
黑女人也是
And the girl, too.
把他们带到格林维尔拍卖会
And I want you to take 'em to the Greenville auction
卖掉他们
and sell 'em.
两个都是
Both of 'em.
分开卖
Separately.
这个…
And this one...
便宜卖
you will sell him cheap.
在格林维尔…
In Greenville...
应该有某种纪录处
there should be some sort of a records office.
你已知道她被卖的时间
You know when she was sold...
她的卖家
you know where she came from,
还有她的名字
and you know her name.
她叫什么名字？
What is her name?
布希达
Broomhilda.
什么？
- What?
布希达
- Broom-hilda.
布希达？
Broomhilda?
她的主人是德国人？
- Were her owners German?
你怎么知道？
- Yeah, how you know?
她不是在卡洛肯庄园出生 她由德国女主人冯夏夫养大
She wasn't born on the Carrucan plantation. She was raised by a German mistress, the Von Shafts.
她也会说一点德语
She speak a little German, too.
你妻子？
Your wife?
她小时候… 她的女主人教她用德语沟通
When she was little, her mistress taught her so she'd have somebody to speak German with.
让我搞清楚
Well, let me get this straight.
你的奴隶妻子会说德语 她的名字叫布希达冯夏夫
Your slave wife speaks German and her name is Broomhilda Von Shaft?
对
Yep.
大家叫我希达
They call me Hildi.
（田纳西州）
（家中黑奴制服）
我们进入这些庄园时
When we gain access to these plantations,
我们要假装演戏
we'll be putting on an act.
你要饰演一个角色
You'll be playing a character.
不好看？
No?
在演戏过程中，你绝不能穿帮
During the act, you can never break character.
了解吗？
Do you understand?
好，不能穿帮
Yeah. Don't break character.
你的角色是侍从
And your character is that of The Valet.
什么意思？
What that is?
是仆人的好听说法
That's a fancy word for servant.
侍从？
Valet?
决哥，现在你能选你角色的服装
And now, Django, you may choose your character's costume.
你要让我挑选自己的衣服？
Youse gonna let me pick out my own clothes?
那还用说
But of course.
这一区禁止黑鬼骑马
It's against the law for niggers to ride horses in this territory.
他是我的侍从，我的侍从不走路
This is my valet. My valet does not walk.
我说黑鬼骑马…
- I said niggers on horses...
他叫做决哥，他是自由民 他想骑什么都行
- His name is Django. He's a free man. He can ride what he pleases.
在我的地盘不行 在我的黑鬼面前不行
Not on my property. Not around my niggers, he can't.
亲爱的先生
My good sir,
或许初次见面搞砸了
perhaps we got off on the wrong boot.
容我再来一次
Allow me to unring this bell.
我叫做金史华兹医生 这是我的侍从决哥
My name is Dr. King Schultz. This is my valet, Django.
这些是我们的马，东尼和费兹
And these are our horses, Tony and Fritz.
班尼特先生？
Mr. Bennett?
我耳闻你是绅士和商人
I've been led to believe that you are a gentleman and a businessman.
因此我们从德州到田纳西州
And it is for these attributes we've ridden from Texas to Tennessee
来跟你谈判
to parley with you now.
我想买你的一个黑人女孩
I wish to purchase one of your nigger gals.
你和你的侍从从德州到田纳西州
You and your Jimmie rode from Texas to Tennessee
来买我的一个黑人女孩？
to buy one of my nigger gals?
没有事先约好？
No appointment, no nothin'?
恐怕如此
Oh, I'm afraid so.
要是我说我不喜欢你
Well, what if I was to say I don't like you?
或你的臭屁黑鬼
Or your fancy-pants nigger?
还有我啥都不卖
And I wouldn't sell you a tinker's damn.
你会怎么说？
Now what you got to say about that?
班尼特先生
Mr. Bennett.
如果你是商人，我耳闻你是
If you are the businessman I've been led to believe you to be,
我有五千个理由让你改变心意
I have 5,000 things I might say that could change your mind.
进来吧，喝点凉的
Well, come on inside and get yourself somethin' cool to drink.
或许我们在谈生意时
Oh, maybe while we discuss business,
你能吩咐你的美丽黑人
you could provide one of your loveliest black creatures
带决哥参观你的宏伟领地
to escort Django here around your magnificent grounds.
没问题
Oh, well, absolutely!
- 贝蒂娜 - 是，大老爹
Betina. Yes sir, Big Daddy?
你说你的侍从叫啥？
What's your Jimmie's name again?
- 决哥 - 决哥
- Django. - Django.
贝蒂娜，带决哥…
Betina, sugar, could you take Django there
到处逛逛，介绍珍奇美景
and take him around the grounds here and show him all the pretty stuff.
遵命，大老爹
As you please, Big Daddy.
班尼特先生，我得提醒你，决哥是自由民
Oh, Mr. Bennett, I must remind you, Django is a free man.
不能把他当奴隶看待
He cannot be treated like a slave. He... within the bounds of good taste,
合乎礼仪的作法是 必须向对待我一样对待他
he must be treated as an extension of myself.
了解，史华兹
- Understood, Schultz.
- 贝蒂娜甜心 - 是
Betina, sugar? - Yes'm?
决哥不是奴隶 决哥是自由民，了解？
Django isn't a slave. Django is a free man, you understand?
对待他不能像是对待这里的黑人
You can't treat him like any of the other niggers around here,
他跟这里的黑人都不一样，懂吗？
'cause he ain't like any of the other niggers around here. You got it?
你要我把他当白人？
You want I should treat him like white folks?
不对
No.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I said.
那我不知道你要怎样，大老爹
Then I don't know what you want, Big Daddy.
我明白了
Yes, I can see that.
镇上那个穷白人玻璃工叫啥名字？
What's the name of that peckerwood boy from town that works with the glass?
他妈在制材场做事
His mama work over at the lumberyard.
- 你是说杰瑞 - 就是他，杰瑞
- Oh, you mean Jerry. - That's the boy's name. Jerry!
- 甜心，你知道杰瑞吧？ - 是，大老爹
You know Jerry, don't you, sugar? - Yes'm, Big Daddy.
没错，就像对杰瑞一样对待他
- Well, that's it, then.You just treat him like you would Jerry.
刚才那间房子是“大房子”
That house we just left from is The Big House.
大老爹这样叫，因为很大
Big Daddy call it that 'cause it's big.
那里是食品室
That there is the pantry.
大老爹把死动物储藏在那里
That's where Big Daddy hang all his dead meat.
可怜的松鼠
Po' little squirrels.
你替你的主人做什么？
What you do for your massa?
没听到他说我不是奴隶？
Didn't you hear him tell you I ain't no slave?
- 你真是自由之身？ - 对，我是自由之身
- So you really free? - Yes, I's free.
你是说你自己想穿成这样？
You mean you wanna dress like that?
- 贝蒂娜，我要问你一件事 - 你要干嘛？
- Betina, I need to ask you somethin'. - What you want?
我在找三个白人，三兄弟，监工
I'm lookin' for three white men. Three brothers. Overseers.
- 姓毕，听过吗？ - 毕？
Their name is Brittle. You know 'em? - Brittle?
对，姓毕 毕约翰、毕艾利斯、毕罗杰
- Yes, Brittle. John Brittle, Ellis Brittle, Roger Brittle,
有时也叫小拉杰
sometime called Lil Raj.
我没听过
I don't know them.
他们可能用化名
They could be usin' a different name.
- 他们应该是去年来这里的 - 你是说夏佛兄弟？
They woulda come to the plantation this past year. - You mean the Shaffers?
或许，三兄弟？
- Maybe. Three brothers?
他们在这里？
They here?
能指出其中一个吗？
Could you point one of 'em out to me?
一个在那里的草地
Well, one's over in that field.
卡洛肯大佬会不高兴
Old Man Carrucan ain't gonna appreciate this, now.
她在主人家工作 让她破相就不妙了
She work in the house, John. You could mess her skin up, and you gonna mess her up
她会变得一无可取
and she ain't gonna be worth... she ain't gonna be worth a damn thing.
你的圣经上说
Now, your Bible say...
听着，我说过是我逼她的
Look, I told you that I was one that made her do it.
- 准备好了？ - 她不想跟我逃跑
You ready? She didn't wanna run off with me. If anybody should be gettin' whupped now,
要打就打我，约翰
it should be me. It should be me, John.
我在这里很久了，你早就认识我
Now, I been here long enough, you know me, you know me a long time, now.
卡洛肯主人会不高兴，她是家奴
You know Massa Carrucan ain't gonna appreciate this. She's a... she's a house slave.
She a house slave, she can't be...
我求你，拜托 你不是就想要我哀求你
On my knees. I'm asking you this, please. Ain't this what you want?
约翰，拜托
I'm keeping it funny for you. Now, John, please.
我跪下了，约翰
L's on my knees, John.
我喜欢你乞求的贱样
I like the way you beg, boy.
你想找的是那个人吗？
Is that who you was lookin' for?
对
Yep.
另外两个呢？
Where the other two at?
在马棚旁，在教训小裘蒂弄破蛋
They by the stable, punishin' Little Jody for breakin' eggs.
他们鞭打小裘蒂？
They whippin' Little Jody?
指出方向给我看
Point me in that direction.
走到那棵树，再继续走那边
You go to that tree and keep goin' that-a way.
去找来跟我的白人同伴
Go get that white man I came here with.
- 快点 - 不要，拜托
- Come on, now. - No, no, please!
快点，丫头
- Come on, girlie. - Please!
快点  把你绑好了
Come on. Get you set up now.
“上帝说，汝之恐惧”
"And the Lord said, 'The fear of ye..."
“与汝之敬畏 将如同世间的所有禽兽”
"...and the dread of ye shall be on every beast of the earth."'
把手伸好
Come here now, woman!
再不把手伸好你就完了
You'd better give me that arm!
好，她准备好了
OK, she's ready!
看你以后还敢不敢弄破蛋
And after this, we'll see if you break eggs again.
毕约翰
John Brittle!
记得我吗？
You remember me?
我喜欢你死的样子
I like the way you die, boy.
死王八蛋！
Goddamn son of a bitch!
哀求我啊
Keep it funny!
大家想看精彩的？
Y'all wanna see somethin'?
不要
No!
他们是谁？
Who were they?
那是大约翰
That's Big John,
那是小拉杰
and that's Lil Raj.
艾利斯呢？
Where's Ellis?
在原野上窜逃的那个人
He's the one hightailin' it across that field right now.
- 确定是他？ - 对
- You sure that's him? - Yeah.
- 肯定？ - 不明白
- Positive? - I don't know.
- 你不明白自己肯不肯定？ - 我不明白“肯定”是什么意思
- You don't know if you're positive? - I don't know what "positive" mean.
- 就是确定 - 对
- It means you're sure. - Yes.
- 什么“对”？ - 对，我确定那是毕艾利斯
- "Yes," what? - Yes, I'm sure that's Ellis Brittle.
我肯定他死了
I'm positive he dead.
决哥！
Django!
大家冷静，我们不想伤害任何人
Everybody calm down. We mean no one else any harm.
你们两个小丑是谁？
Who are you two jokers?
我是金史华兹医生 美国刑法制度的…
I am Dr. King Schultz, a legal representative
合法代表
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America.
我左边这位是决哥自由民 他是我的副手
The man to my left is Django Freeman. He's my deputy.
我口袋里有通缉令
In my pocket is a warrant,
由德州奥斯汀巡回审判法官 亨利艾伦罗德米克签署
signed by Circuit Court Judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin, Texas,
下令逮捕和俘虏，无论生死
for the arrest and capture, dead or alive,
毕约翰、毕罗杰、毕艾利斯
of John Brittle, Roger Brittle and Ellis Brittle.
他们化名为夏佛兄弟
They were goin' by the name Shaffer.
你以为他们姓夏佛 但这群屠夫的本姓是毕
You know them by the name of Shaffer, but the butchers' real name was Brittle.
他们是通缉犯，因谋杀罪依法通缉
These are wanted men. The law wants 'em for murder.
现在我重申
Now, I reiterate,
通缉令上明令“无论生死”
the warrant states dead or alive,
所以我和自由民先生当场处决他们
so when Mr. Freeman and myself executed these men on sight,
我们是在法律范围内行动
we were operating within our legal boundaries.
我明白你满腔怒火
I realize passions are high,
但我得警告你
but I must warn you,
采取致命武力…
the penalty for taking deadly force
违抗法庭官员行使职责的刑罚是
against an officer of the court in the performance of his duty
你会被吊死
is you'll be hung by the neck until you're dead.
现在请容我拿出通缉令给你检查
Now, may I please remove the warrant from my pocket so you may examine it?
给我
Gimme.
满意了？
Satisfied?
请还我
May I have that back, please?
滚出我的地盘
- Get off my land.
立马走人
- Posthaste.
尽快带走尸体，快走人
Load up the bodies as quickly as you can and let's get outta here.
对，是那两个王八蛋
Yeah, that's them sons-a-bitches.
快点
Come on, men!
有胆别走，黑鬼
We're coming for you, nigger!
除非他们先开枪
Now, unless they start shootin' first,
不准有人开枪
nobody shoot 'em.
那样对这些小丑太客气了
That's way too simple for these jokers.
我们要把哈黑鬼的白人鞭死
We're gonna whup that nigger-lover to death.
我还要亲自把那个黑鬼阉了
And I'm gonna personally strip and clip that garboon myself.
可恶
Damn.
戴这玩意我啥都看不到
I can't see fuckin' shit outta this thing.
准备好了没？
We ready or what?
等等，我弄一下眼洞
Hold on, I'm fuckin' with my eyeholes.
靠，愈弄愈糟
Oh... Oh, shit. I just made it worse.
- 这烂玩意谁做的？ - 维拉的妻子
Who made this goddamn shit? - Willard's wife.
不然你们自己做面罩啊
- Well, make your own goddamn masks!
别误会，大家都感谢珍妮的服务
Look, nobody's sayin' they don't appreciate what Jenny did.
要是我只是在袋子上钻洞 我能钻得更好
Well, if all I had to do was cut a hole in a bag, I coulda cut it better than this!
罗伯，你呢？看得到吗？
What about you, Robert? Can you see?
有点遮到
Not too good.
不转头看你会比较清楚
I mean, if I don't move my head I can see you pretty good, more or less.
但骑马时面罩会乱动 好像瞎子骑马
But when I start ridin', the bag's movin' all over, and I'm ridin' blind.
靠
- Shit. - Yeah.
我也愈弄愈糟
I just made mine worse.
Oh, God.
谁还有备用的？
Anybody bring any extra bags?
没啦，谁会有备用的
No, nobody brought an extra bag!
- 我只是问问 - 骑马时一定要戴吗？
I'm just askin'. Do we have to wear 'em when we ride?
靠，骑马时不戴…
Oh, well, shitfire! If you don't wear 'em as you ride up,
- 就白搭了 - 戴这玩意我看不到
that just defeats the purpose! Well, I can't see in this fuckin' thing!
我无法呼吸，戴这玩意我不能骑马
I can't breathe in this fuckin' thing and I can't ride in this fuckin' thing!
去你们的，我要回家了
Well, fuck all y'all! I'm goin' home!
我看我老婆辛苦整天
Now, I watched my wife work all day
替你们这群忘恩负义的王八蛋 一口气钻了30个袋子
gettin' 30 bags together for you ungrateful sons-a-bitches,
我却只听到批评、批评、批评！
and all I can hear is criticize, criticize, criticize!
以后别叫我或我老婆帮忙
From now on, don't ask me or mine for nothin'!
听着 别忘了我们在这里的目的
Now, look, let's not forget why we're here.
那边的山区有个黑鬼杀手 我们要给他教训
We got a killer nigger over that hill there! And we gotta make a lesson out of him.
我搞糊涂了 到底要不要戴面罩？
OK, I'm confused. Are the bags on or off?
大家都觉得面罩是个好主意
I think we all think the bag was a nice idea. Yeah.
但没针对谁，面罩能做得更好
But, not pointin' any fingers, they coulda been done better.
干脆这次不戴面罩
So how 'bout no bags this time,
下次把面罩做对再披挂上阵
but next time we do the bags right and then we go full regalia.
- 好主意 - 我投你一票
- I like that idea a lot. - You get my vote, Robert.
等一下
Wait a minute!
我没同意
I didn't say no bags.
但大家都看不到
But nobody can see.
- 所以咧？ - 看到会比较好
So? So it'd be nice to see.
妈的，这是袭击，大家都看不到
Goddamn it! This is a raid! I can't see, you can't see!
那又怎样？最重要的是马看得到 这是袭击
So what? All that matters is can the fuckin' horse see! That's a raid!
王八蛋！
Sons of bitches!
我啥都看不到
I can't see shit!
他在那里 把黑鬼从马车下撵出来
There he is! Get that nigger out from under that wagon!
也把他麻吉从马车下撵出来
And get that nigger-lover outta the wagon!
- 黑鬼不在下面，大老爹 - 什么？
That nigger ain't down here, Big Daddy! - What?
- 他们在耍我们 - 那他们在哪里？
- They tricked us! Well, where are they?
再会了
Auf Wiedersehen.
正中目标
Bull's-eye.
看他们落跑了
Look at 'em run.
孬种常会那样
Yeah, cowards tend to do that.
可恶
Goddamn it!
想试试吗？
Would you care to?
啥都看不见
Can't see shit outta this!
- 他要逃走了 - 我会干掉他
- He's getting away. - I got him.
大老爹要逃走了
Big Daddy's getting away.
我会干掉他
I got him.
干掉他了
Got him.
你是天生好手
The kid's a natural.
你怎知布希达前主子是德国人？
How you know Broomhilda's first masters was German?
布希达是德国名字
Broomhilda is a German name.
这表示命名者必然是德国人
If they named her, it stands to reason they'd be German.
你的庄园有很多女生叫布希达吗？
Lots of gals where you're from named Broomhilda?
布希达是一个角色名称
Broomhilda is the name of a character
在最著名的德国传奇中
in the most popular of all the German legends.
有故事在讲布希达？
There's a story about Broomhilda?
对，没错
Oh, yes, there is.
你熟悉吗？
- Do you know it?
每个德国人都知道那个故事
- Oh, every German knows that story.
要我告诉你吗？
Would you like me to tell you?
布希达曾是公主
Well, Broomhilda was a princess.
她是万神之王沃坦的女儿
She was a daughter of Wotan, god of all gods.
总之她爸非常气她
Anyway, her father is really mad at her.
她做了什么？
What she do?
我不太记得了
I can't exactly remember.
她就是不服从他
She disobeys him in some way.
于是他把她送到山顶
So he puts her on top of the mountain.
布希达在山上？
Broomhilda's on a mountain?
这是德国传奇，一定会有山
It's a German legend, there's always going to be a mountain in there somewhere.
他安排一只喷火龙守着山
And he puts a fire-breathing dragon there to guard the mountain.
他用地狱之火把她围住
And he surrounds her in a circle of hellfire.
布希达会一直受困在那里
And there, Broomhilda shall remain.
除非有英雄鼓足勇气拯救她
Unless a hero arises brave enough to save her.
有英雄挺身而出吗？
Does a fella arise?
有，决哥，事实上有
Yes, Django, as a matter of fact, he does.
那个人叫做齐格弗里
A fella named Siegfried.
齐格弗里有拯救她吗？
Does Siegfried save her?
那是一场壮举
Quite spectacularly so.
他攀登那座山，因为他不害怕
He scales the mountain, because he's not afraid of it.
他屠杀那只龙，因为他不怕他
He slays the dragon, because he's not afraid of him.
他穿过地狱之火
And he walks through hellfire...
因为布希达值得
because Broomhilda's worth it.
我懂他的感觉
I know how he feel.
我开始能体会了
I think I'm just starting to realize that.
听着，决哥
Now, look, Django...
你肯定会拯救你深爱的女人
I don't doubt that one day you'll save your lady love...
但我不能昧着良心让你去格林维尔
but I can't let you go to Greenville in a good conscience.
密西西比州的奴隶拍卖镇 不是你该去的地方
A slave auction town in Mississippi isn't the place for you to visit.
无论自不自由，都太危险了
Free or not, it's just too dangerous.
但我问你一个问题
But let me ask you a question.
你喜欢赏金猎人的工作吗？
How do you like the bounty hunting business?
杀白人还有钱领？
Kill white folks and they pay you for it?
干嘛不喜欢
What's not to like?
我得承认，我们是好搭档
Now, I have to admit, we make a good team.
我以为你不爽我杀了大约翰和小拉杰
I thought you was mad at me for killin' Big John and Lil Raj.
那件事你是有点热心过度 但正常来说是好事
Yeah, on that occasion you were a tad overzealous, but normally, that's a good thing.
这个冬天想要合伙吗？
How'd you like to partner up for the winter?
“合伙”是指什么？
What you mean "partner up"?
你跟我合作直到冬天结束
You work with me through the winter till the snow melts...
我给你三分之一的赏金
I give you a third of my bounties.
这个冬天挣点钱，等到雪溶化
So we make some money this winter, and when the snow melts,
我亲自带你去格林维尔
I'll take you to Greenville myself
我们会查出你妻子被送去哪里
and we'll find where they sent your wife.
你何必关心我会怎样？
Why you care what happen to me?
何必关心我能不能找到老婆？
Why you care if I find my wife?
坦白说
Frankly...
我从没赋予任何人自由
I've never given anybody their freedom before.
现在既然有，多少感觉对你有责任
And now that I have, I feel vaguely responsible for you.
加上德国人遇到实际的齐格弗里 这可就大条了
Plus, when a German meets a real life Siegfried, that's kind of a big deal.
身为德国人，我有义务帮你…
As a German, I'm obliged to help you on your quest
冒险营救你心爱的布希达
to rescue your beloved Broomhilda.
你熟能生巧了
You got her.
“我要射杀白人领钱”  先生怎么了？
What happened to Mr. "I Wanna Shoot White Folks For Money"?
他儿子在旁
- His son's with him.
很好，他死时有家人陪
- Well, good. He'll have a loved one with him.
或许还能说遗言
Maybe even share a last word.
比多数人死得痛快
That's better than most of them get.
他算是赚到了
Damn sight better than he deserves.
把枪放下
Put down the rifle.
别担心，我不是气你
Don't worry, I'm not mad at you.
拿出史密提毕考的传单
Let's take out Smitty Bacall's handbill.
大声念出
Read it aloud.
当作今天学到一课
Consider that today's lesson.
“通缉，无论生死”
"Wanted. Dead or alive."
“史密提毕考和史密提毕考一…”
Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall
- 一帮人 - “一帮人”
- Gang. - "Gang."
“因谋杀和马车…”
"For murder and stagecoach..."
“抢劫”
robbery.
“70…” - Seven-zero-zero-zero.. - Seven thousand.
Thousand.
“7000元悬赏史密提毕考”
"$7,000 for Smitty Bacall."
“1500元悬赏他的…”
$1,500 for each of his...
“一帮同…”
gang...
同…？
- Mem...
“同伙”
- "Members."
“史密提毕考帮的已知同伙如…”
Known members of the Smitty Bacall Gang are as follas:"
- 如下 - “如下”
- Follows. - "Follows."
“丹尼麦可斯、杰拉德纳许…”
"Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash and..."
疯子克雷格库。恩
Crazy Craig Koons.
史密提毕考就是这种恶棍
That is who Smitty Bacall is.
如果史密提毕考22岁时立志开农场 这张传单就绝不会存在
If Smitty Bacall wanted to start a farm at 22, they would never have printed that.
但是史密提毕考想要抢劫马车
But Smitty Bacall wanted to rob stagecoaches
他为达目的滥杀无辜
and he didn't mind killing people to do it.
你想要效法我替天行道救你爱妻？
Do you want to save your wife by doing what I do?
这就是我的使命
This is what I do.
我杀人和卖尸体领钱
I kill people and sell their corpses for cash.
这具尸体值7000元
This corpse is worth $7,000.
别再龟毛了，射杀他
Now quit your pussyfooting and shoot him.
爸？
Pa?
爸！
Pa!
拿去
Here.
留着这张史密提毕考的传单
You need to keep this Smitty Bacall handbill.
为什么？
- Why?
这是幸运符 切记随身携带首次赏金的传单
- It's good luck. You always keep the handbill of your first bounty.
很准
That's accurate.
医生、决哥，你们好啊
Doctor, Django, how the hell are ya?
你们干掉谁了？
Who the hell-a you got there?
威尔森罗尔帮
The Wilson-Lowe Gang.
威尔森罗尔帮是谁？
Who the hell is the Wilson-Lowe Gang?
坏蛋威尔森与更狠的巴比罗 还有他们的三个手下
Bad Chuck Wilson and meaner Bobby Lowe and three of their acolytes.
别管他们，他们又不会跑掉
Well, just leave 'em out here, they ain't going nowhere.
外头冰天雪地，进来喝点咖啡
Why don't you come in then out of the snowy snow and get yourselves some coffee.
昨天我们庆生，有些蛋糕
We had a birthday yesterday. Got some cake.
很好
Pretty good.
（经过收获丰厚的寒冬之后）
（决哥和史华兹医生下山）
（前往…）
（密西西比州）
Move along!
Move it, boy!
继续走，向拍卖区行进
Keep movin'. Get on up on that auction block.
别因泥地放慢脚步，继续走
Don't let that mud slow you down. Keep going.
继续走
Keep goin'!
“布希达冯夏夫”
"Broomhilda Von Shaft.
“27岁”
Age 27.
“右脸颊烙了“R”字”
'R' on right cheek."
（凯文康迪）
“凯文康迪”
Calvin Candie.
他拥有密西西比第四大的棉花庄园 糖果园
He owns the fourth biggest cotton plantation in Mississippi: Candyland.
糖果园？
Candyland?
- 原来你听过 - 所有奴隶都听过糖果园
Oh, so you've heard of it. Ain't no slave ain't heard of Candyland.
显然你妻子在那里
Well, apparently, that's where your wife is...
那个恶霸名绅拥有她
and that's the repellant gentleman
希望她在主人家工作，不是田野
who owns her. Let's just hope she works in the house, not in the field.
她才不是田野的黑奴
Oh, no, she ain't no field nigger.
她很漂亮
She... she pretty.
她也很会说话
And she talk good, too.
但自从她被痛鞭
But when they tore her back up and then they...
脸上还烙了逃跑的“R '’字
burned that runaway "r" on her cheek...
她就毁了
they goddamned her.
她不是田野的黑奴 但她也不再够格在主人家做事
She ain't no field nigger but she ain't good enough for the house no more either.
- 她会被逼去当慰安妇 - 慰安妇？懂了
They gonna try to make her a comfort girl. What's a comfort...?
我是自由之身说休想
Not while I got freedom.
我有枪就休想
Not while I got my gun.
那我们要出价买她吗？
So do we offer to buy her?
姑且…
So...
说…
say...
有个人想要买只马
a man wants to buy a horse.
需要买只马
Needs to buy a horse.
他去农人的农场，敲农人的门
He walks up to the farmer's farm, and he knocks on the farmer's door
要求买农人的马 知道农人会怎么说？
and asks the farmer to buy his horse. And do you know what the farmer says?
农人拒绝
The farmer says no.
去他妈的农人，我用偷的
Well, I say fuck that farmer, and I'm stealin' that horse.
有道理，但你说变成偷马贼
Fair enough. But now you're a horse thief,
偷马贼会被吊死
and they hang horse thieves.
更不用说马会送回原主人 因为马仍是他的财产
Not to mention the horse goes back to its original owner because the horse is still his property.
我们需要她，也需要销售收据
We need her and we need a bill of sale.
但我们不买她的话要怎么获得她？
Well, if we ain't gonna try to buy her, then how we gonna get her?
我能提供行动备案吗？
May I offer an alternative plan of action?
说吧
Go ahead.
买家去农人的农场，敲农人的门
So... the man walks up to the farmer's farm, he knocks on the farmer's door...
不是要求买马，而是农场
and asks not to buy the horse, but the farm.
开出高得离谱的报价
And makes an offer so ridiculous,
农人不得不答应
the farmer is forced to say yes.
- 我们要出价买糖果园？ - 不，那太大了
- We gonna offer to buy Candyland? - No, it's far too big.
但显然这个农人不只在意农场
But apparently this farmer ain't all about the farm.
你多了解曼丁果格斗？
How much do you know about Mandingo fighting?
什么？
What?
你能煞有其事地扮成…
Can you convincingly masquerade as someone
曼丁果格斗的专家吗？
who is an expert on Mandingo fighting?
为什么？
Why?
因为我的角色是 来到格林维尔的德国大买家
Because my character is that of a big money buyer from Dusseldorf,
想要洒钱打入曼丁果格斗赛
here in Greenville to buy my way into the Mandingo fight game.
你的角色是我雇来的曼丁果专家
And your character is a Mandingo expert I hired to help me do it.
即江湖人称的“独眼查理”
They call that "One-Eyed Charley."
- 你好 - 晚安
Bonjour.
我的黑人小妞
我们来见凯文康迪先生
We're here to see Mr. Calvin Candie.
请进
Entraz.
谢谢
Thank you.
你要我扮演黑人奴隶商？
You want me to play a black slaver?
这种人最贱了
Ain't nothin' lower than a black slaver.
黑人奴隶商比黑奴总管更贱
A black slaver is lower than the head house nigger...
伙伴，就是贱到不行
and, buddy, that's pretty fuckin' low.
那就演贱一点
Then play him that way.
演好你的黑人奴隶商
Give me your black slaver.
Along came the 219 Toot! Toot! Peanut butter!
史医生
Dr. Schultz!
- 喜重逢啊 - 摩盖先生
- Good to see you again! - Mr. Moguy.
感谢协助安排这次约见的机会
Thank you for your assistance in creating the opportunity
别客气，这是我的本分
- for this appointment. - Nonsense, it's my job.
这位就是久闯大名的独眼查理吧
So this is the One-Eyed Charley I've heard so much about.
对，这位是决哥自由民
Yes, this is Django Freeman.
决哥，这位是凯文康迪的律师 李奥奈摩盖
Django, this is Mr. Candie's lawyer, Leonide Moguy.
叫我李奥就好
Just call me Leo.
凯文在凯撒大帝室，请跟我来
Calvin's in the Julius Caesar room. You all wanna follow me?
你跟康迪先生认识多久了？
How long have you been associated with Mr. Candie?
我和凯文的父亲11岁时 一起上寄宿学校
Oh, Calvin's father and I were about 11 when we went to boarding school together.
凯文的祖父付钱让我读完法学院
Calvin's father's father put me through law school.
几乎能说我被栽培成凯文的律师
One could almost say I was raised to be Calvin's lawyer.
几乎跟黑奴一样
One could almost say youse a nigger.
你说什么？
What did you say?
- 我说……  - 没事，他在耍冷
- I said... - Nothing, he's just being cheeky.
见康迪先生前还要注意他哪些事？
Anything else about Mr. Candie that I should know before I meet him?
有，他是亲法国人士
Yes, he is a bit of a Francophile.
上流人士不都这样？
What civilized people aren't?
他喜欢称作康迪男士胜于康迪先生
And he prefers Monsieur Candie to Mr. Candie.
（随他高兴）
他不会说法语 别跟他说法语，他会很糗
He doesn't speak French. Don't speak French to him, it'll embarrass him.
回到上面！转身！
Get back on top, now! Turn around!
很好
There you go. There you go.
你为什么想要进入曼丁果业？
Why do you want to get in the Mandingo business?
不必由你的副手正式介绍？
You don't intend to allow your second to make the proper introductions?
少废话，回答问题
Quit stalling, now. Answer the question.
糟糕的真相？
The awful truth? I'm bored.
我太闷了，这似乎很好玩
This seems like a good bit of fun.
过来坐
Well, come on over.
现在正在格斗，很好玩
We got us a fight goin' on that's a good bit of fun.
陪我去吧台吧
Won't you accompany me to the bar?
室内要脱帽，白人，连我都知道
You don't wear a hat in the house, white man. Even I know that.
- 史医生 - 万分高兴
- Dr. Schultz. - What a rare pleasure.
继续斗，黑鬼
Keep fighting, niggers.
容我补充，也很荣幸
- And I might add, an honor.
幸会，请坐，荣幸之至
- Honor to meet you. Please have a seat, the pleasure's all mine.
看自由民决哥想喝什么
Get free man Django here whatever he wants.
我要甜茶和波本酒
And I'll have sweet tea and bourbon.
利用你的重量，很好
Use your weight, boy, use your weight! There you go.
他高大又强壮多了
He's much bigger and stronger!
拼了啦
Come on, now!
他没照我的话做，乱七八糟
He's not doing what I told him, for God's sakes.
赞啦，鲁吉
拼了，这是一场殊死战
Come on, now, boy! It's a fight to the death!
你到底要不要干掉他？
You either hit him or are you ain't?
大佛莱，加油
Big Fred, come on!
把他转过来，快点
Turn him around! Now...
加把劲
Use your strength, boy!
快点，加把劲
Come on, now! Use your strength!
很好
There you go!
你瞧
Look at that.
看吧，我就说出手要更重
See, I told you to put some more power in there.
照我的话做
Do what I told you, boy!
很好
There you go!
不要！
- No!
照我的话做
- Do what I told ya!
挖出他的眼珠，挖出他的眼珠
Blind him black, boy! Blind him black!
不，鲁吉
Oh, no, Luigi.
好耶
杀掉他
Finish him.
快点，杀掉他
Go on, boy, finish him!
名不虚传大佛莱，绝对值回票价
That's why they call him Big Fred.
再会，鲁吉
- Worth every penny.
快起来，休息一下
- Well, arrivederci, Luigi. Come on up, now, boy. Get yourself a rest.
表现很好，好极了
You did a fine job. A real fine job.
摩西黛
Mercedes.
龙舌兰
Tequila.
怎么称呼？
What's your name?
决哥
Django.
怎么拼？
Can you spell it?
D一J一A一N一G一O
D-J-A-N-G-O.
处决的决
The D is silent.
我知道
I know.
安贝托，走吧
摩盖先生，照顾我的新宠
Mr. Moguy, want you to take care of my new boy here.
给他有软床的房间 找个黑妞替他吹喇叭
You find him a room with a soft bed, then you bring him up a pony to lick his pole.
但明早准备好来糖果园，明白没？
But you be ready to travel to Candyland tomorrow morning, now, ya hear?
- 遵命，康迪男士 - 走之前
Yessir, Monsieur Candie. Before you go,
罗斯柯，给佛莱一瓶啤酒
Roscoe, get Fred here a tall beer.
好好享用，你应得的
You enjoy that, boy. You've earned it.
遵命
Yessir.
你叫什么名字？
- What's your name, boy?
他的名字是决哥自由民
- His name is Django Freeman.
你哪里找到他的？
Where'd you dig him up?
决哥和我是有缘千里来相会
A fortuitous turn of events brought Django and myself together.
我对你略有耳闻
I've heard tell about you.
听说你宣称那些曼丁果选手烂透了
I heard you been telling everybody them Mandingos ain't no damn good.
市场上的曼丁果黑奴都不值得买
Ain't nothin' nobody is sellin' is worth buyin'.
我很好奇  你凭什么成为曼丁果专家？
I'm curious... what makes you such a Mandingo expert?
我好奇是什么让你这么好奇
I'm curious what makes you so curious.
- 你说什么？ - 冷静，布奇
- What did you say, boy? - Calm down, Butch.
没有恶意
No offense given...
也不以为意
none taken.
康迪男士
Monsieur Candie...
我建议你有问题直接问我
I'd appreciate if you could direct your line of inquiry toward me.
首先
One...
你没有饮料，想喝点什么吗？
you do not have anything to drink. Can I get you a tasty refreshment?
- 好，我要啤酒 - 太好了
- Yes! I'll have a beer. - Wunderbar.
罗斯柯，给大胡子男一瓶啤酒
Roscoe, a beer for the man with the beard,
我要玻里尼亚潜水采珠人 兰姆酒不能少
and I will have a Polynesian Pearl Diver. Do not spare the rum.
医生
Doc...
我是经验丰富的奴隶商 你是新手
I am a seasoned slaver. You are, well, you are a neophyte.
我只是想确定这个牛仔…
I'm simply tryin' to ascertain if this cowboy here
有没有占你便宜
is takin' advantage of you.
恕我直言，康迪男士
With all due respect, Monsieur Candie...
我找你不是想要你的指点
I didn't seek you out for your advice.
而是想要以市场最高价 买个格斗黑人
I sought you out to purchase a fighting nigger at above top-dollar market price.
你同意见我时，我以为…
Now I was under the impression, when you granted me an audience,
这次是来谈生意的
it would be to discuss business.
我们还不谈生意
Well, we weren't talkin' business yet.
我们谈我的好奇心
We were discussin' my curiosity.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗斯柯，可可，去外头玩
Roscoe, Coco, go outside and play.
夏芭，你留下
Sheba... you stay right there.
我知道你不是指我
I know you didn't mean me.
- 干杯 - 德国人
- Prost! - German.
据摩盖所说
Now, according to Moguy,
如果我跟你做生意
if I do business with you,
就是跟你们俩做生意
I'm doing business with both y'all.
他挑人，你付钱，是吗？
He does the eyeballin', you the billfold? Is that it?
直截了当，但差不多
Well, you don't make it sound too flattering, but more or less, yeah.
所以…
So...
好小子 摩盖说你查看了我的黑人选手
Bright Boy... Moguy tells me you looked over my African flesh
全看不上眼，是吗？
and you was none too impressed?
没有高档货
Not for top dollar.
那我们没什么好谈了
Well, then, we got nothin' more to talk about.
你想要向我买普通选手
You see, you wanna buy a beat-ass nigger from me,
我就只有那些货色
those are the beat-ass niggers I wanna sell so...
他不想买你想卖的黑人
He don't wanna buy the niggers you wanna sell.
他想买你不想卖的黑人
He wants the nigger you don't wanna sell.
我不卖我不想卖的黑人
Well, I don't sell the niggers I don't wanna sell.
你不会卖最好的
Well, you won't sell your best.
连第二好的也不卖
You won't even sell your second best.
那第三好的呢？你也不想卖
But your third best...? You don't want to sell him either.
但如果我开出高到离谱的价格 你就不得不考虑
But if I made you an offer so ridiculous you'd be forced to consider it...
谁晓得会不会有谱？
who knows what could happen?
你怎么定义“离谱”？
And what do you consider ridiculous?
天赋异秉的奇人 独一无二的黑人？
For a truly talented specimen, the right nigger?
决哥，你说多少？
How much would you say, Django?
12000元
Twelve thousand dollars.
两位，你们原本令我好奇
Well, gentlemen, you had my curiosity,
现在你们引起我的注意了
but now you have my attention.
威利，威利
Willie. Willie.
停车，停车
Hold up! Hold up.
- 早安，各位 - 史医生啊
- Good morning, gentlemen. - Good Dr. Schultz.
- 美好的早晨，对吧？ - 好到没得比
- Beautiful morning, isn't it? - You couldn't have picked a better one.
请上车，跟我们去兜风
Please, won't you take a ride with us here in the Victoria.
感谢赏光
Oh, thank you very much.
你的马能绑在后面
You can tie your horse up back there.
决哥
Django.
我跟友人、同僚的不同之处
Where I part company from many of my phrenologist colleagues
在于我相信有一种等级能超越智慧
is I believe there is a level
超越天资、超越忠诚
above bright, above talented,
黑人梦寐以求的典范
above loyal that a nigger can aspire to.
比如出现万中选一的黑人
Say, one nigger that just pops up in 10,000.
非比寻常的黑人
The exceptional nigger.
好日子吧，好小子？
Bright day Bright Boy?
太阳出来了
Sun is up.
照耀我们所有人
Shining on all of us.
请坐，医生
- Have a seat, doc. - Thank you.
荣幸至极
Quite an honor.
- 与有荣焉 - 谢谢
- The honor is all ours. - Thank you.
但我相信随着时间
But I do believe that, given time,
像这位好小子一样的不寻常黑人
exceptional niggers like Bright Boy here...
即使仍不常见
become if not frequent...
但会变得更常见
more frequent.
对吧？
Bright Boy,
你就是万中选一
you are that one in 10,000.
这个局是要跟得上，不是赶不上
The name of the game is keep up, not catch up, nigger.
- 敢碰枪，你就死定了 - 各位，冷静
- Touch your guns, you die. - Everybody, calm down!
综观全局，没有恶意
Now I saw the whole thing. No harm done.
- 没搞错？这黑人… - 我说没有恶意
Are you kidding me? - This nigger just... - I said no harm done!
手不准碰枪
Now take your hand off your pistol!
布奇，你也是
Butch, that means you too.
所有人别再敌视我的客人
Everybody stop antagonizing my guest.
胡特，上马
Hoot! Get back up on your horse.
他弄断我的锁骨
He broke my collarbone!
搞屁，谁快来扶胡特上马
For God's sake, somebody please help Hoot here back up on his goddamn horse.
- 遵命，老板 - 你是走运的黑人
- Yessir, boss. - Oh, now you are one lucky nigger.
你最好听你老板的话，白人小子
You better listen to your boss, white boy.
我要跟你在月光下漫步
Oh, I'm gonna go walking in the moonlight with you.
你想牵我的手？
You wanna hold my hand?
威利，送我们回家
Willie, take us home.
好了，开始行进
Start moving!
叫奴隶快走
Head 'em out!
你眼睛有问题吗？
You got a problem with your eyeball, boy?
- 没有 - 要我把你眼睛踹正吗？
No, sir. You want a boot heel in it?
不用
No, sir.
那就少瞪着我
Then you keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
再给我臭脸，就给你好看
You flash that bad look at me again, I'll give you a reason not to like me.
快走，黑人
Now move, nigger!
你们这些黑人会见识到老子的厉害
You niggers are gonna understand something about me.
我比这些白人更可怕
I'm worse than any of these white men here.
别慢吞吞了，别死盯着我了
You get the molasses out your ass, you keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
他活力旺盛呢
He is a rambunctious sort, ain't he?
确实
Indeed.
能暂停一下吗？ 我想跟我的伙伴说句话
May we stop for a moment so I may put a word in my man's ear?
我见到糖果园的选手想必会很在意
You know, I'm expecting to fall in love once I see the specimens at Candyland,
所以在那之前
so before that moment,
我希望跟我的密友有个… 机密的策略会议
it would be good if I could have  a confidential strategy meeting with my confidant.
能透露你在干嘛吗？
You mind telling me what the hell you doing?
我已确认布希达在糖果园
I confirmed that Broomhilda's at Candyland.
- 确定是她？ - 他没说她的名字
- You're sure it's her? - He didn't call her by name,
但有个年轻女孩 背后有鞭打疤痕，会说德语
but she's a young lady, whip marks on her back and speaks German.
虽然在现况下这种假设并不乐见
Now, while it's not wise to assume,
但八九不离十
in this instance, I think it's pretty safe.
重点是
Point being,
不要满脑子想着报复
don't get so carried away with your retribution.
你忘记我们来这里的目的
You lose sight of why we're here.
- 你以为我忘记了？ - 没错，别再杠上康迪
- You think I lost sight of that? - Yes, I do. Stop antagonizing Candie.
你会让我们穿帮，会害死我们
You're going to blow this whole charade, or more than likely get us both killed.
我可不想死在 美国密西西比州的契卡索郡
And I, for one, don't intend to die in Chickasaw County, Mississippi, USA.
我不会杠上他，我会智取他
I'm not antagonizing him. I'm intriguing him.
你对这群可怜的奴隶鬼叫耶
You're yelling abuse at these poor slaves.
我想起有个人…
I recall the man
命令我在别人儿子面前杀人
who had me kill another man in front of his son
他连眼睛都没眨一下
and he didn't bat a eye.
你记得吧？
You remember that?
我当然记得了
Yeah, of course I remember.
你教过我，这是我的世界
What you said was that this is my world...
想要翻身难免得弄脏手
and in my world you gotta get dirty.
所以我照做，把手弄脏
So that's what I'm doing. I'm gettin' dirty.
你有点曲解我的意思
Well, you're paraphrasing a tad, but...
但主旨相差不远
that was the general gist.
糖果园见
See you at Candyland.
好，黑人们，继续走
All right, niggers, back at it.
你也是，月光
That means you too, Moonlight.
不会吧
I'll be. D'Artagnan!
达太安！
小子，干嘛蠢到逃跑？
Now, boy, why do a fool thing like run off?
我不能再格斗了，康迪男士
I can't fight no more, Monsieur Candie.
你当然能
Yes, you can.
你也许赢不了，但你还能打
You might not be able to win, but your ass can fight.
史东赛佛先生，叫这些死狗闭嘴 我无法专心思考
Mr. Stonesipher, would you please shut these goddamn dogs up? - I cannot hear myself think!
安静，玛夏，小声
- Quiet down, Marsha! Marsha, hush up! Marsha!
玛夏，小声
Hush up! Hey!
把这些狗牵走
Get these goddamn dogs away from this nigger!
- 小子，别趴在树上了 - 是的
Come on now, boy... get on out that tree. Yessir.
他逃跑多久？
How long was he loose?
一晚，白天
A night. Day.
再半晚
Half the other night.
他逃离多远？
How far he get off the property?
约20英里，以他瘸腿来说挺远的
'Bout 20 miles off the prop. Pretty far considering that limp he got.
摩盖先生 周五达太安预计跟谁对打？
Mr. Moguy, who was D'Artagnan supposed to fight on Friday?
这群新人的其中一个
One-a this new lot.
看他现在的样子 连瞎眼的印地安人都不会赌他赢
Well, way he looks now, a blind Indian wouldn't bet a bead on him.
拜托，康迪男士，我不能再打了
Please, Monsieur Candie, I ain't got it in me no more.
够了…不准乞求
- Now, now, now, now, now. - I can't... Now, no beggin'.
别激起我的软心肠
No playin' on my soft heart.
- 你闯祸了 - 是
- You in trouble now, son. - Yessir.
我付了500元买你
I done paid $500 for you.
我付500元时
When I pay $500,
我预期一名黑奴挂掉前打五场
then I expect to get five fights out of a nigger'fore he roll over and play dead.
是的
- Sir.
你要了解我是生意人
You got to understand that I'm runnin' a business here.
- 你打过三场 - 但我赢了每一场
- You fought three fights. - But I won every one.
对，没错
Yes, you did. Yes, you did.
但上一场，你差点输了
But that last one, you muddled the line between winnin' and losin'. Yessir.
事实依然不变
Still, the fact remains:
我付500元，我就要五场比赛
I pay $500, I want five goddamn fights!
不然我的500元怎么办？
So what about my $500?
我的500元怎么办？
What about my $500?
你要补偿我吗？
You gonna reimburse me?
你懂不懂“补偿”的意思啊？
You even know what "reimburse" means?
我会补偿你
I'll reimburse you!
你愿意？
You Will?
对
Yep.
你愿意付500元
You'll pay $500
买这个几乎独眼 连扫把都拿不动的废人？
for practically a one-eyed old Joe ain't fit to push a broom?
不，他不愿意
No, he won't.
他只是受够你玩弄他
He just tired of you toyin' with him is all.
事实上，我也是
Matter of fact, so am I.
但我们不会付一分钱买那个黑仔
But we ain't payin' a penny for that pickaninny.
他没用了 对吧，医生？
Ain't got no use for him. Ain't that right, doc?
你听到他了
You heard him.
你得原谅史东赛佛先生 吓得目瞪口呆
You're gonna have to excuse Mr. Stonesipher's slack-jawed gaze.
他这辈子没见过你这种黑人
He ain't never seen a nigger like you ever in his life.
史东赛佛先生，对吧？
Ain't that right, Mr. Stonesipher?
没错
That right.
就此而言
For that matter...
我也没看过
nor have I.
现在
Now...
既然你们不付钱买这个黑仔
seein' as you won't pay a penny for this pickaninny here...
不介意他随我处置吧？
you won't mind me handlin' this nigger any way I see fit?
他是你的黑人
He's your nigger.
史东赛佛先生？
Mr. Stonesipher?
让玛夏和她的狗同伴 送达太安下黑人地狱吧
Let Marsha and her bitches send D'Artagnan to nigger heaven.
玛夏！
Marsha!
玛夏，咬他
Marsha, hey, get him!
咬他，咬他
Get 'im, get 'im!
Yeah!
你老板的脸色发青 目睹这种媲美黑人格斗的血腥场面
Your boss looks a little green around the gills for a blood sport like nigger fighting.
不，他只是不习惯看到 人被狗大卸八块
Nah, he just ain't used to seein' a man ripped apart by dogs is all.
你就习惯？
You are used to it?
我比他习惯美国作风
I'm just a little more used to Americans than he is.
康迪男士
Now, Monsieur Candie...
准备出发了吧
whenever you're ready.
我们走了5小时让你炫耀货色 该赶路了
We rode five hours so you could show off your stock. Let's get to it.
目前为止，如果他是示范 没啥了不起
'Cause as of now, if he's an example, I ain't impressed.
走吧
Follow me.
（哈里斯费德公司）
（凯文康迪）
让他们在左边排好队
Line 'em up to the left here now, boy.
站直
Stand up straight, now!
上去那里
Get up there.
上去那里，快点
Get up there, boy. Come on.
叫你们排队，快排队 排好，站直
Give me a line! Give me a line! Get in line there! Straighten up!
你好，史提芬，老兄
Hello! Stephen, my boy!
你好啊，老兄个头
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Hello, my ass.
这个骑马的黑鬼是谁？
Who this nigger up on that nag?
史提芬，你早餐吃钉子？ 怎么了？干嘛话中带刺？
Stephen, you have nails for breakfast? What's-a matter? Why you so ornery?
- 你很想我吧 - 是的
- You miss me? - Oh, yessir.
我想死你了
I miss you like a hog miss slop!
就像宝宝想念妈妈的咪咪
Like a baby miss mammy's titty.
我想你就像想念鞋里的石子
I miss you like I misses a rock in my shoe.
我问你，这个骑马的黑鬼是谁？
Who this nigger on that nag?
嗨，白人跟班
Hey, Snowball?
想要知道我或我马儿的名字 直接问我
Wanna know my name or the name of my horse, you ask me.
骑马仔，你叫谁白人跟班？
Just who the hell you callin' "Snowball," horse boy?
我会瞬间把你拖下马摔落泥地 快到你的头会打转
I'll snatch your black ass off that nag there and in the mud so fast...
史提芬…
- ...make your head spin. - Stephen, Stephen, Stephen.
别坏了兴致，决哥是自由民
Let's keep it funny. Django here's a free man.
- 这个黑人？ - 没错
- This nigger here? - That nigger there.
好歹让我介绍你们俩
Let me at least introduce the two of you.
决哥，这是跟你一样拽的黑人 史提芬
Django, this is another cheeky black bugger like yourself, Stephen.
史提芬，这是决哥 你们俩应该互相讨厌
Stephen, this here's Django. You two oughta hate each other.
凯文，这黑人算哪根葱 让你觉得有必要款待？
Calvin, just who the hell is this nigger you feels the need to entertain?
决哥和他的灰衣朋友史医生 是顾客
Django and his friend in gray here, Dr. Schultz, are customers.
他们是我们的客人
And they are our guests, Stephen.
你这老不休该殷勤招待他们
And you, you old decrepit bastard, oughta show them every hospitality.
- 明白了没？ - 遵命，他的话我知道
- You understand that? - Yessir. Him I understand.
但我不明白为何要忍受这黑人吐槽
But I don't know why I got to take lip off this nigger.
你不必懂原因，明白了没？
You don't have to know why. Do you understand?
- 遵命，我知道了 - 很好
Yessir. I understand. Well, good.
他们要过夜 去楼上准备好两间客房
They're spendin' the night. Go up in the guest bedrooms and get two ready.
他要住在主屋？
He gonna stay in The Big House?
史提芬，他是奴隶商，是特例
Stephen, he's a slaver. It's different.
- 住在主屋？ - 你有意见吗？
- In The Big House? - Well, you got a problem with that?
没，小的没意见
Oh, no. I ain't got no problem with it,
只是这脏黑人离开时
if you ain't got no problem with burnin' the bed, the sheets,
你不心疼把床、被单、枕头都给烧了
the pillowcases, everything else when this black-ass motherfucker's gone!
那是我的问题，我的东西随我烧
That is my problem! They are mine to burn!
你现在的问题是留下好印象
Now your problem right now is makin' a good impression!
还不快解决问题，把客房准备好
And I want you to start solvin' that problem right now and get them goddamn rooms ready!
遵命，康迪男士
Yessir, Monsieur Candie.
快去
Go on, now.
不敢相信你带个黑人来住主屋
Can't believe you brought a nigger to stay in The Big House.
你爸会从坟里爬出来
Your daddy rollin' over in his goddamned grave.
瞧他说话  嘴巴愈来愈贱
Man, the lip on him. He's gettin' worse and worse. Now...
我的美丽姊姊呢？
Where is my beautiful sister?!
她来了
There she is!
史医生，这位迷人的南方美女 是我守寡的姊姊
Dr. Schultz, this attractive Southern belle is my widowed sister.
亲爱的，看到你就精神百倍
Darlin', you are a tonic for tired eyes.
容我介绍拉拉莉康迪费兹威利
May I present to you Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly.
切斯特、罗德尼、小查理 全过去畜栏那里
Chester, Rodney, Chicken Charly. Y'all get your ass over by that pen.
- 快点，查理，赶快 - 快走，快点
- Come on, Charly. Come on, now! - Let's go.
你们知道地点，冲过去
You know where it is. Like you on a rope!
这里的黑人不准走路，只准跑步
Niggers don't walk around here, niggers run!
康迪男士
Monsieur Candie?
关于你聊到的那个黑人女孩
Yeah. About that matter about the nigger girl you were talking about?
黑人女孩？
Nigger gal?
对，我记得你提到她会说德语
Yeah, I believe you mentioned she spoke German.
对，希达，她怎样？
Yes! Hildi, what about her?
你想在挑货色之前 能送她到我房间吗？
Do you think before the demonstration, you could send her around to my room?
你这色胚，有何不可
You little dickens, you. I don't see why not.
史提芬，带他们进房之后 去叫希达
Stephen, when you get through showin' them to their rooms, go fetch Hildi,
让她洗得香喷喷 送她到史医生的房间
get her cleaned up and smellin' real nice, and sent over to Dr. Schultz's room here.
康迪男士，其实有件事我还没告诉你
Actually, Monsieur Candie, sir, there's-a somethin' I ain't told you 'bout yet.
- 什么？ - 希达在地窖
- What? - Hildi in the Hot Box.
她跑到那里干嘛？
What's she doin' there?
不然你以为咧？她受到惩罚啊
What you think she doin' there in the Hot Box? She bein' punished.
- 她做了什么？ - 她又逃走了
- What she do? - She run off again.
要命，史提芬 我不在时跑掉多少人？
Jesus Christ, Stephen, how many people ran away while I was gone?
- 两个 - 她何时逃的？
- Two. - When did she go?
昨晚，今早被带回来
Last night. They brung her back this morning.
史东赛佛的狗把她咬得多惨？
How bad did Stonesipher's dogs tear her up?
她运气好，狗都去追达太安了
Lucky for her, they was out chasin' D'Artagnan's ass.
比尔和寇帝去找她 发现她就带她回来
Bill and Cody went lookin' for her, found her, brung her back.
现在她伤痕累累
Now, she a little beat-up.
但她从树林逃走是自找罪受
But she done that to her own damn self runnin' through them damn bushes and shit.
她在地窖里多久了？
How long she been in the box?
你以为多久？当然是整天
How long you think she been in there? All damn day.
那个小贱人要再关十天
And the little bitch got ten more days to be in there.
- 还是放她出来 - 放她出来？为什么？
- Still, take her out. - Take her out? Why?
因为老子说的，没为什么
Because I said so, that's why.
史医生是我的客人 希达是我的黑奴
Dr. Schultz is my guest. Hildi is my nigger.
南方的好客就是要以客为尊
Southern hospitality dictates I make her available to him.
- 可是康迪男士，她逃走耶 - 要命，史提芬
- But, Monsieur Candie, she run off. - Jesus Christ, Stephen.
养个会说德语的黑奴
What is the point of havin' a nigger that speaks German
却不让她服侍德国客人有何意义？
if you can't wheel 'em out when you have a German guest?
我明白时机不当 但你还是要放她出来
Now, I realize it is inconvenient, but still, you take her ass out.
遵命
Yessir.
拉拉莉，你和柯拉负责…
Lara Lee! Will you and Cora be responsible
帮希达洗净和打扮，献给史医生
for gettin' Hildi cleaned up and presentable for Dr. Schultz here.
- 当然
Of course, darlin'.
两位 亲爱的 我道歉 我旅途奔波累到不行
Now, gentlemen, I do apologize, but I am weary from our travels beyond words.
我该眯一下了
It is time for me to rest my tired eyes.
你们都听到老板的话了 把她拖出来
Y'all done heard the man! Get her ass up outta there!
柯拉，过来
Cora! Come here!
去帮她洗干净  再把她送到那个医生…
Get over there and get her cleaned up, bring her back over here to Dr...
- 他说你叫什么名字？史艳文？ - 史华兹
- What he say your name is? Shoots? - Schultz.
史华兹
Schultz.
- 把她拖出来，赶快 - 是的
Get her back over here. Hurry up, girl. Yessir.
快点，起来
Come on, girl. Stand up.
不要！不要！
No,no!
你要跟我来？ 还是想睡在那里的地窖？
Is you comin' with me or is you gonna sleep in that little box over yonder?
女士们好
Hello, ladies.
史医生，容我介绍布希达
Dr. Schultz. May I introduce to you Broomhilda?
希达，这位是史医生
Hildi, this is Dr. Schultz.
幸会，布希达
It's a pleasure to meet you, Broomhilda.
久仰大名了
I've heard a lot of good things about you.
不是每个黑奴都会说德语，妙吧
Well, it's not every nigger speaks German, don't ya know.
当我望着你，布希达
As I look at you now, Broomhilda,
我能看出你激起的一切热情 完全有理可循
I can see all the passions you inspire are completely justified.
这位医生会说德语
The doctor here speaks German.
我听说你也会说德语？
And I've been informed you do as well?
露一手，说一点德语
Go ahead, girl. Speak a little German.
（很荣幸跟您说德语）
不是盖的
Astonishing.
（请进，小姐）
- 我该送来… - 感激不尽
- And I shall bring you... - Much obliged.
（替你倒杯水好吗？)
Ja.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
（请见谅）
（我发觉你很久没说德语了）
（所以我会慢慢说）
（我跟你说德语只是 以免康迪的人偷听）
不好意思
Pardon.
（你很美丽）
Danke.
（我和我们的一个共同朋友）
（历经重重困难）
（长途跋涉）
（为了找你，小姐）
（为了解救你）
（请喝）
（我和我们共同朋友的目的）
（就是带你远走高飞）
（我没有任何朋友）
（有，你有）
（谁？)
（我不能告诉你）
（我们的共同朋友喜欢搞神秘）
（这个朋友在哪里？)
（就站在那扇门的后方）
（答应我你不会尖叫？)
（说“我答应”）
嗨，小麻烦
Hey, Little Trouble Maker.
你还真是乌鸦嘴
You silver-tongued devil, you.
- 赶快 - 这些好了，柯拉小姐
- Hurry up, girl. - These ready, Miss Cora.
不，他们今晚喝酒
No, no, no, they drinkin' tonight.
去楼下拿康迪男士喜欢的大罐红酒
Go downstairs, get the big jug with the red stuff Monsieur Candie like, hear?
- 你的俏臀别档路 - 是你的菜吧
- Get your big pretty ass out the way. - You know you like it.
你懂我爱什么菜
That's 'cause you knows what I like.
快准备好面包
Come on with these biscuits, girl.
康迪男士，他们都是优秀的选手 无庸置疑
Look, Monsieur Candie, they were all fine specimens, no doubt about it.
不过前三名显然是参孙…
But the best three by far were Samson...
- 另一个叫什么名字？ - 高迪
- What's that other one's name? - Goldie.
高迪
Goldie.
还有爱斯基摩乔
And Eskimo Joe.
对了，为何他叫做爱斯基摩乔？
By the way, why is he called Eskimo Joe?
你猜不透黑人的昵称是怎么来的
You never know how these nigger nicknames get started.
他名叫乔，或许某天他说他很冷 谁晓得
His name was Joe, maybe one day he said he was cold. Who knows?
不管怎样，参孙是最强的
Well, regardless, Samson's your best.
大家心里有数
We all know that.
你绝不会卖他，我能理解 他是冠军选手
You will never sell him, and I can see why. He's a champion.
这三人都是冠军选手
All three are champions.
参孙是冠军选手
Samson's the champion.
另两个尚可
Them other two pretty good.
- 凯文，这黑人竟敢放肆… - 没关系
Calvin, now what's this nigger you let... It's all right.
你必须了解，康迪男士
You have to understand, Monsieur Candie,
无可否认我是黑人格斗赛的新手
while admittedly a neophyte in the nigger fight game,
但我略有欧洲巡回马戏团的背景
I do have a little bit of a background in the European traveling circus.
是吗？
Is that right?
因此我在甄选上有远大概念
Hence, I have big ideas when it comes to presentation.
我需要的不只是大汉
I need something more than just a big nigger.
还需要会耍威风
Yeah, he needs to have panache.
- 需要什么？ - 耍威风
- Need to have what? What? - Panache.
- 要能招揽顾客的意思 - 招揽顾客，好
- A sense of Showmanship. - Showmanship, yes.
我要能够把他宣传成黑力士
I want to be able to bill him as The Black Hercules.
- 黑力士，太正点了 - 是黑猩猩吧
The Black Hercules, isn't that clever? More like Nigger-les.
我引述之前的话
“我会付最高价买…”
"I would pay top dollar for...
“独一无二的黑人”
'the right nigger."'
我不是说爱斯基摩乔本身不好
Now I'm not saying that Eskimo Joe is the wrong nigger, per se.
但他是独一无二吗？
But is he right as rain?
史医生，我敢说黑人格斗赛中
Oh, Dr. Schultz, I will have you know there is no one in the nigger fight game
没人比我…
that appreciates the value of showmanship
- 更重视招揽顾客 - 没人可比
more than Monsieur Calvin J. Candie here.
但别忘了黑人格斗赛的至高真理
Nobody. But one must not forget the most important thing in the nigger fight game.
会获胜的黑人最重要
And that is a nigger that can win fights.
那该是你的前几名优先考量
Now that should be your first, second, third, fourth, and fifth concern.
先有获胜的黑人
Now, after you have that, and you know you have that,
你才能开始实行崇高计划
then you can start to implement a grand design.
换句话说，事情有轻重缓急
In other words, first thing is first.
事情有轻重缓急
First thing's first.
我看你们两个很来电
I see you two gettin' on.
满意极了
Famously.
康迪男士
Oh, Monsieur Candie,
你无法想像四年没听到母语的感觉
you can't imagine what it's like not to hear your native tongue in four years.
我无法想像待在波士顿两周的感觉
Well, hell, I can't imagine two weeks in Boston.
待在波士顿两周！ 康迪男士，你超瞎的
Two weeks in Boston! Monsieur Candie, you a mess!
待在波士顿两周！
Two weeks in Boston!
我无法表达用母语谈话的喜悦
I can't express the joy I felt conversing in my mother tongue.
希达是很迷人的谈话对象
And Hildi is a charming conversation companion.
小心，史医生
Well, be careful now, Dr. Schultz.
你可能会变成黑人粉丝
You might-a caught yourself a little dose of nigger love.
黑人粉丝是很强烈的情绪
Nigger love's a powerful emotion, boy.
就像一池黑沥青 一旦沾上就洗不掉
It's like a pool of black tar. Once it catches your ass, you're caught.
是的，会卡住
Yessir, you stuck.
医生，我总觉得…
I don't know, doctor.
你尽管用德语的甜言蜜语把妹
You can lay on all the German sweet talk you want,
但看来这小妞更属意决哥
but it looks like this pony's got big eyes for Django.
想必如此
Well, naturally.
威猛的老鹰才能吸引她的注意
It is the soaring eagle that attracts her attention,
不是干瘪的小鸡
not the plucked chicken.
史医生，别看轻自己
Dr. Schultz, don't be so down on yourself.
你是短小精悍的欧洲绅士
You are quite the dapper European gentleman.
盘子洗干净，卖力点，听到没？
You got to clean these dishes, you got to put your elbow in these dishes, you hear me?
你认识那个黑人，对吧？
You know that nigger, don't you?
- 谁？ - 还问谁？
- Who? - "Who?"
别唬我，你知道我在说谁
Don't "who" me, bitch. You know who I'm talkin' about.
那个座上客？
At the table?
我不认识他
I don't know him.
你不认识他
- You don't know him.
- 不认识 - 还有呢？
- No. - "No," what?
没了
- No, sir.
你不会骗我吧？
You wouldn't lie to me, now, would you?
好
OK.
你说了算
Yeah. If you say so.
无疑爱斯基摩乔是出色的黑人
Eskimo Joe's a quality nigger, no doubt about it.
但如果是我出钱
But if it was my money,
我不会花12000元买他
I wouldn't pay no $12,000 for him.
那你要出什么价？
What would your price be?
要是我情愿当凯子
Well, if I was inclined to be generous...
我不明白为何我情愿当凯子
and I don't know why I would be inclined to be generous...
9000元
9,000.
或许
Maybe.
史医生
Dr. Schultz,
让我再次澄清 这整场协商的来龙去脉
let me reclarify how this whole negotiation came about.
不是我主动要卖你黑人
You see, it wasn't me who came to you to sell a nigger.
当然不是
Sure wasn't.
- 是你找上我要买黑人 - 当然是
It was you who approached me to buy one. - Sure was.
好小子讨价还价的9000元价码
- Now, that $9,000 figure Bright Boy's been bandyin' about,
不会相差太远 但要我用这价钱卖爱斯基摩乔
that ain't too far off from right. And if I wanted to sell Eskimo Joe for that,
- 我无时无刻都能卖 - 随时
- I could do so any day of the week. - Any day.
但如你在格林维尔所说 我不想卖他
But, like you said in Greenville, doctor... I don't want to sell him.
只是你的离谱开价12000元
It was only your ridiculous offer of $12,000
让我甚至考虑一下
that made me even consider it.
康迪男士，你确实富有说服力
You know, Monsieur Candie, you do possess the power of persuasion.
有何不可？康迪男士，成交了
Why not? Monsieur Candie, you have a deal.
爱斯基摩乔，12000元
- Eskimo Joe, $12,000.
赞啦，医生，明智的决定
- Hooray, doctor. Hooray. And a wise decision that is.
然而，那是一笔为数不小的巨款
However, that is a tremendous amount of money.
如同你有摩盖先生，我也有律师
And the way you have your Mr. Moguy, I have a lawyer.
名叫塔托的锱铢必较哥
Persnickety man named Tuttle.
我需要塔托先生拟定法律合约
And I would need my Mr. Tuttle to draw up a legal contract
这样我才安心用大笔钱来换人
before I'd feel comfortable exchanging that amount of money for flesh.
更不用说让爱斯基摩乔 给我选定的医生检查
Not to mention having Eskimo Joe examined - by a physician of my choosing.
- 当然了 - 不然等我回来
- Naturally. So, say I return in about...
五天后
- ...five days time.
五天后？
- Five days?
跟塔托先生讨论
With my Mr. Tuttle.
然后我的塔托先生与你的摩盖先生
And then my Mr. Tuttle and your Mr. Moguy
能乔好彼此之间更繁密的细节
can hash out the finer details between themselves.
我赞成，医生，太赞了
I say splendid, doctor. Splendid.
各位
Gentlemen...
容我举杯祝贺
may I propose a toast.
敬爱斯基摩乔
To Eskimo Joe.
或是该称他为黑力士？
Or shall we call him The Black Hercules?
敬黑力士
To The Black Hercules.
黑力士
The Black Hercules.
敬黑力士
To The Black Hercules.
你说得对，医生 这称号确实是假掰
You was right, doctor. That name do have pan-ass.
希达，倒满我的酒杯
Hildi, top my drink off.
希达，你喜欢在主屋服侍主桌吗？
So, Hildi, how you like servin' at the big table in The Big House?
康迪男士跟你说话就要回答
When Monsieur Candie talk to you, you answers.
非常喜欢，康迪男士
I like it a lot, Monsieur Candie.
比在热滋滋的地窖里 或被拖过满地荆棘好多了吧
It's a lot better than sizzlin' in that Hot Box or draggin' your ass through a bramble bush.
但或许不如取悦曼丁果黑奴 来得有趣吧，甜妞？
But maybe it's not quite as much fun as gettin' to pleasure all them Mandingos,
- 老天，她喜欢那些黑人，当然了 - 喜欢参孙吗？
- Sugar bear? - Oh, Lord, she like them niggers. - Sure do. - Like Samson?
不喜欢
No, sir.
康迪男士
You know, Monsieur Candie,
医生可能有兴趣看希达的背疤
the doctor here might be interested in seein' Hildi's peeled back,
在他的家乡想必黑人是稀有品种
seein' as how they don't have many niggers where he come from.
史医生，你跟希达独处时
Dr. Schultz, when you was alone with Hildi, here,
你们只是说德语 还是你有让她卸下衣衫？
did you just speak German or did you get to take her clothes off?
- 不，我们只有谈话 - 所以你没看过她的背部？
No, we just talked and... Oh, so you haven't seen her back?
我没有…
- I haven't...
不，史提芬说得对 你可能会觉得很有趣
- No, no, no, no. Stephen's right, you might find this interesting.
希达，快脱掉衣服
Hildi, go on, take off your dress.
给史医生看你的背部，赶快
Show Dr. Schultz your back here.
凯文，我才刚替她着装打扮漂亮
- Go on. - Calvin. I just got her all dressed up and lookin' nice.
可是拉拉莉，史医生来自杜塞道夫
But, Lara Lee, Dr. Schultz is from Dusseldorf.
那里没有黑人 他是学医的
They don't got niggers there. He is a man of medicine.
我相信他会迷上黑人的忍痛力
I'm sure it would fascinate him, the niggers' endurance for pain.
黑人很强悍，无庸置疑
These niggers are tough, Dr. Schultz, no doubt about it.
希达的背上被鞭了四下
Hildi's got somethin' like four lashes on her back.
- 拉拉莉被鞭一下就会昏倒 - 当然了
Lara Lee just get one, she'd lose her goddamn mind.
- 你看，医生，像是图画 - 凯文！
- Sure would. - Look at that, doctor. - It's like a paintin'. Look at that. - Calvin!
我们在用餐 没人想看她背部的鞭痕
We are eating. Ain't no one wanna look at her whipped up back.
好吧…
Fine. Fine, fine, fine, fine.
那晚餐后，史提芬 晚餐后
After dinner, then, Stephen. After dinner.
两位，喝白兰地时再看吧
During the brandies, gentlemen?
柯拉，带这女孩下去
Cora, come get this girl!
- 她的衣服乱掉了 - 是，女士
- She a mess. - Yes, ma'am.
你怎么衣衫不整？ 我才刚替你打扮好，快进来
Why are you all undone? I just got you done up. Come on in here.
宝贝，你惹毛史提芬了 你要避开他
Baby, you on Stephen bad side, and you need to be on his blind side.
你说你不认识他
You say you ain't know him.
我说，你说你不认识他
I said, you said you ain't know him.
我不认识
- I don't.
你认识
- Yes, you do.
史提芬先生
Mr. Stephen...
我不认识
I don't.
你为什么骗我？
Why is you lying to me?
我没有
I ain't.
那你为什么哭？
Then why is you crying?
你吓到我了
You scarin' me.
我为什么吓到你了？
- Why is I'm scaring you?
因为你很可怕
- Because you scary.
下午跟希达说德语
To speak German this afternoon with Hildi
肯定是充实心灵
was positively soul-enriching.
医生，听了我很窝心
Doctor, that warms my heart to hear that.
你待在这里
You stay right here.
你之前指出 你愿意割爱希达
You indicated earlier you'd be willing to part with Hildi.
对，当然好了
Why, yes. Yessiree bob, I did.
既然如此
In that case,
容我提出另一个建议
allow me to propose another proposition.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
赶快，该死
Hurry up, goddamn it!
- 康迪男士 - 史提芬
- Monsieur Candie... - Stephen!
你刚打断史医生
You just interrupted Dr. Schultz here.
抱歉，史医生 我的耳朵愈来愈不行了
I'm sorry, Dr. Schultz. My ears ain't worth a damn these days.
原谅他
Excuse him.
康迪男士，能到厨房说句话吗？
Monsieur Candie, could I get a word with you in the kitchen?
你是要我离席？
You mean get up out of my chair?
麻烦了
- If'n you could manage it.
- 为什么？ - 是甜点的事
- Why? - It's about dessert.
甜点怎么了？
- What about dessert?
我宁可私下讨论
I'd rather discuss that in private.
我们要吃白蛋糕
We're having white cake!
厨房里会出什么乌龙？
What sort of melodrama could be brewing back there?
您说得是，康迪男士 小的自己处理
You right, Monsieur Candie. You right. I'll handle it myself.
书房里见
Meet me in the library.
我不懂你干嘛不进来 讨论一下这些黑人
I just can't understand why you won't come talk to these niggers.
要是出状况，你就怪我
Shit get fucked up around here, you blame me.
好啦，史提芬老友，我很快进去
Fine! Fine. Friend Stephen, I will be along momentarily.
了解
Yessir.
两位，如你们所见
Well, gentlemen, as you can see,
厨房的黑奴手艺绝对一流
talented as they are, no doubt, in the kitchen,
但偶尔还是需要大人监督
from time to time, adult supervision is required.
失陪一下
If you'll excuse me a moment.
能清理餐盘了
You may clear the dinner service.
听到没，快去
You heard him. Go on! Get! Hurry up, girl.
赶快
So,
史医生 说个马戏团故事当余兴节目吧
Dr. Schultz, why don't you regale us with a tale of the circus.
马戏团？
The circus?
怎么回事？
What is the matter?
那些混蛋不是来买曼丁果黑奴
Them motherfuckers ain't here to buy no Mandingos.
他们想要那个女孩
They wants that girl.
史提芬，你在说什么鬼？
Stephen, what the hell are you talking about?
我是说他们把你当猴耍
They playing your ass for a fool is what I'm talking about.
他们不是来买大只佬黑奴
They ain't here for no musclebound Jimmie.
是冲着这女人来的
They here for that girl.
什么女孩？希达？
Wh... What girl? Hildi?
对，希达，她和决哥是旧识
Yeah, Hildi. Her and Django, them niggers know each other.
他刚买了爱斯基摩乔
He just bought Eskimo Joe.
- 他付钱了吗？ - 还没，可是…
- Did he give you any money? - No! Not yet. But...
那他买个屁，还没咧，随便
Then he ain't bought diddly. Not yet, nohow.
但他正要买…
But he's just about to buy
他意中人的时候被我打断
who he come here to buy when I interrupted him.
“谢谢你，史提芬” 不客气，凯文
"Thank you, Stephen." You're welcome, Calvin.
你怎么兜在一起的？
Where you gettin' all this?
他们何必费尽心机 买一个不值300元的…
Why would they go through all that trouble for a nigger with a chewed up back, ain't worth $300?
瑕疵黑鬼？
那是因为决哥和希达相爱
They doin' it 'cause that nigger Django's in love with Hildi.
她可能是他老婆
She probably his wife.
至于那个德国人干嘛 帮那个目中无人的王八黑鬼
Now, why that German gives a fuck who that uppity son of a bitch
我打死也想不透
is in love with, I'm sure I don't know.
如果她是他们的目标
If she's who they want...
那干嘛扯上整个曼丁果？
why this whole snake oil pitch about Mandingos, then?
你不会鸟300元的交易
You wouldn't pay no never mind to no $300.
但12000元呢？
But that 12,000?
让你们变麻吉，对吧？
That made you real friendly, now, didn't it?
是啊
Yes, it did.
他老婆，是吗？
His wife?
既然这么扯，我早该发现的
If it had been a snake, it would have bit me.
那些胡说八道…
Those lying...
超浪费时间的…
goddamn time-wastin'
王八蛋
sons of bitches.
王八蛋！
Sons of bitches!
我来自纽奥良 所以我很熟悉戏班子
Out of New Orleans, so I have quite a bit of practice with theater types.
你来了
Oh, there you are.
我开始以为你和那欧吉桑私奔了
I was beginning to think that you and that old crow run off together.
那大家会吓死吧
That'd be a hell of a note, wouldn't it?
拉拉莉，我只是去主窗查看
Lara Lee, I was just looking out the big window.
比利克莱许在那里应付…
Billy Crash is out there dealing with some shady slaver
想卖一群小马的可疑奴隶商 麻烦你去那里检查一下小马
trying to sell a passel of ponies. Would you be a dear, go out there and give them gals an eyeball?
- 当然，弟弟 - 谢谢，姊姊
- Of course, brother. - Thank you, darling.
做生意全天无休呢
Yeah. Business never sleeps.
对了，在你离开之前
Apropos, before your exit,
我们在讨论是否能买布希达
we were discussing the possibility of my purchasing Broomhilda.
对，没错，医生
Yes. Yes, we were, doctor.
等一下再谈
And we will again. In a moment.
你的这个小朋友是谁？
Who's your little friend?
这是班
This is Ben.
他是住在这里很久的老仆人
He's a old Joe that lived around here for a long time.
是真的久到不行
And I do mean a long damn time.
老班照顾我爸
Old Ben here took care of my daddy...
还有我爷爷
and my daddy's daddy.
直到他有一天暴毙
Till he up and keeled over one day...
老班也照顾我
Old Ben took care of me.
我是密西西比大庄园主人的儿子
Growing up the son of a huge plantation owner in Mississippi
见过…
puts a white man
一脱拉库的黑人
in contact with a whole lotta black faces.
我这辈子都生活在这里 就在这里糖果园
I spent my whole life here, right here in Candyland...
身边全是黑人
surrounded by black faces.
每天看到他们，日复一日
Now, seeing them every day, day in, day out,
我只有一个问题
I only had one question:
他们为何不出草杀光白人？
Why don't they kill us?
在那里的阳台 50年来每周3次
Now, right out there on that porch, three times a week for 50 years,
老班会用利刀替我爸刮胡子
Old Ben here would shave my daddy with a straight razor.
如果我是老班 我早就给我老爸割喉了
Now, if I was Old Ben, I woulda cut my daddy's goddamn throat
而且根本不必犹豫50年
and it wouldn't have taken me no 50 years to do it, neither.
但他从没有
But he never did.
为何没有？
Why not?
瞧，颅相学
You see, the science of phrenology
可有效理解…
is crucial to understanding
黑人和白人的差异
the separation of our two species.
在这个黑人的头骨中
In the skull of the African here,
攸关服从的部位
the area associated with submissiveness
比地球上任何人类 或任何其他动物都来得大
is larger than any human or any other subhuman species on planet Earth.
如果你检查…
If you examine...
这片头骨
this piece of skull here...
你会注意到三处明显的凹洞
you will notice three distinct dimples.
这里、这里和这里
Here, here and here.
现在
Now...
如果我拿的是牛顿或伽利咯的头骨
if I was holding the skull of an Isaac Newton or Galileo,
这三处凹洞会出现在 头骨最攸关什么的部位
these three dimples would be found in the area of the skull
创造力
most associated with... creativity.
但这是老班的头骨
But this is the skull of Old Ben.
在老班的头骨中
And in the skull of Old Ben,
天资匮乏
unburdened by genius,
这三处凹洞存在于 头骨最攸关什么的部位
these three dimples exist in the area of the skull most associated with...
奴性
servility.
好小子
Now, Bright Boy...
我承认你很聪明
I will admit you are pretty clever.
但如果我拿这支榔头
But if I took this hammer here...
猛槌你的头骨
and I bashed in your skull with it...
你在相同的部位 也有三处相同的凹洞
you would have the same three dimples in the same place...
跟老班一样
as Old Ben.
现在把手掌摊平在桌上
Hey! Now lay your palms flat on that tabletop!
只要你们的手掌离闭那张龟壳桌
If you lift those palms off that turtle shell tabletop,
布奇先生就会用短枪轰了你们
Mr. Pooch is gonna let loose with both barrels of that sawed-off.
今晚宴席问鬼话连篇
There have been a lot of lies said around this dinner table here tonight,
但现在是来真的
but that you can believe!
摩盖先生 麻烦收走挂在他们腰际的枪
Mr. Moguy, would you be so kind as to collect the pistol hanging off these boys' hips here?
- 非常感谢 - 医生
- Thank you ever so much. - Doctor.
讲到哪里了？
Where were we?
驴蛋
Jackass.
想到了
Yes.
我相信你们正准备提案…
I do believe you were just getting ready to make me
买布希达
a proposition to buy Broomhilda.
对吧？
Am I right?
对
Right.
把希达带出来
Bring out Hildi!
过去那里
Get over there yonder.
给我坐在椅子上
Sit your ass in that goddamn...
- 把手摊平在桌上 - 闭嘴
Lay your hand flat on that tabletop. Now shut your mouth!
史医生
Dr. Schultz, in Greenville,
在格林维尔 你自己说“独一无二的黑人”
you yourself said that for the right nigger
你愿意出公认的离谱价钱
you'd be willin' to pay what some may consider is a ridiculous amount.
而我问“你怎么定义离谱”
To which me myself said, "What is your definition of ridiculous?"
你回答“12000元”
To which you said, "$12,000."
既然你们千里迢迢
Now, considering y'all have ridden a whole lot of miles,
经历这么多困难
went through a whole lot of trouble, and done spread a whole lot of bull
瞎掰这么多谎话 只为了买这个俏妞
to purchase this lovely lady right here,
显然布希达其实才是 “独一无二的黑人”
it would appear that Broomhilda is, in fact... the right nigger.
如果你们想要 带着布希达离开糖果园
And if y'all want to leave Candyland with Broomhilda,
价钱就是12000元
the price is $12,000.
我猜你偏好 “不要就拉倒”的协商风格
And I take it you prefer the "take it or leave it" style of negotiation?
没错，医生
Yes, I do, doctor.
按照契卡索郡的法律
You see, under the laws of Chickasaw County,
布希达是我的财产
Broomhilda here is my property.
我能对我的财产随心所欲
And I can choose to do with my property whatever I so desire!
如果你们认为…
And if y'all think my price...
这个黑人的索价太高
for this nigger here is too steep...
我的随心所欲说是…
what I'm gonna desire to do is...
用这支榔头把她槌死
take this goddamn hammer here and beat her ass to death with it!
就在你们两人面前
- Right in front of both y'all!
冷静，大块头
- Easy, big fella.
那样我们就能检查 布希达的头骨里有没有三个凹洞
Then we can examine the three dimples inside Broomhilda's skull!
医生，你的决定怎样？
Now, what's it gonna be, doc?
你的决定怎样？
What's it gonna be?
我能把手离开桌上 拿出我的皮夹吗？
May I lift the hands off the tabletop in order to remove my billfold?
请便
Yes, you may.
这是12000元
That 12.
售出
Sold!
卖给好样的胡子男 还有他好样的黑人
To the man with the exceptional beard and his unexceptional nigger.
- 摩盖先生 - 是，凯文
- Mr. Moguy. - Yes, Calvin?
请开12000元的收据给这两位男士
Will you make these gentlemen a receipt for $12,000, please?
12000元
$12,000.
很高兴跟你们做生意
It was a pleasure doing business with y'all.
两位
Now, gentlemen...
欢迎一起来客厅
if you care to join me in the parlor...
我们要上白蛋糕了
we will be serving white cake.
（布希达冯夏夫）
（凯文康迪，李奥奈摩盖）
干得好，凯文
Well done, Calvin.
请暂停
Excuse me.
请暂停，女士
Excuse me, ma'am?
请停止弹贝多芬了
Could you please stop playing Beethoven?
手别碰竖琴了
Take your hands off the harp!
医生
Doctor!
- 医生，你不能进去 - 史提芬，史提芬
- Doctor, you can't go in there! - Stephen, Stephen.
- 他没事干嘛进去 - 不要紧
He ain't got no business going in there. Let it be.
他只是有点郁闷，我来搞定
He's just a little upset, that's all. I'll handle this.
吃白蛋糕？
White cake?
我不嗜吃甜食，谢谢
I don't go in for sweets, thank you.
你在思索我怎么打败你的？
You brooding about me getting the best of you?
其实我在想 你今天喂狗的那个可怜鬼
Actually, I was thinking of that poor devil you fed to the dogs today.
达太安
D'Artagnan.
我很纳闷大仲马会做何感想
And I was wondering what Dumas would make of all this.
再说一次？
Come again?
亚历山大仲马 《三剑客》的作者
Alexandre Dumas. He wrote The Three Musketeers.
是啊，医生
Yes, of course, doctor.
我想你一定是他的书迷
I figured you must be an admirer.
你以他小说的主角给奴隶命名
You named your slave after his novel's lead character.
如果今天大仲马在场
Now, if Alexandre Dumas had been there today,
我很纳闷大仲马会做何感想
I wonder what he would have made of it.
你怀疑他不会认同？
You doubt he'd approve?
对，他认同的话绝对令人匪夷所思
Yes. His approval would be a dubious proposition at best.
软心肠的法国人
Soft-hearted Frenchie.
大仲马有黑人血统
Alexandre Dumas is black.
- 这是布希达的合约吗？ - 没错
- Are these Broomhilda's papers? - Yes, they are.
- 我能检查吗？ - 当然
- May I? - Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是她的卖契、历年主人
That is her bill of sale, her ownership history,
当然还有她的自由证明
and, of course, her freedom papers, doctor.
有笔和墨水借我吗？
Would you have ink and pen for me?
- 在那个小桌上 - 谢谢
- Right over there on that little table. - Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
布希达冯夏夫
Broomhilda Von Shaft...
你已经是自由的女人了
consider yourself a free woman.
康迪先生
Mr. Candie...
通常，我会说“再会”
normally, I would say auf Wiedersehen.
但因为“再会”的真正意思是 “后会有期”
But since what auf Wiedersehen actually means is "till I see you again"
既然我绝不愿再见到你 对你…
and since I never wish to see you again,
我会说“永别了”
to you, sir... I say, "goodbye."
走吧
Let's go.
来吧
Come on.
等一下，医生
One more moment, doctor!
什么事？
What?
南方这里有个传统
It's a custom here in the South...
一旦交易结束，双方会握手
once a business deal is concluded that the two parties shake hands.
- 意味着诚意 - 我不是南方人
It implies good faith. - I'm not from the South.
但是你…
- But you are...
在我家里，医生
in my house, doctor.
恐怕我得坚持
- So I'm afraid I must insist.
坚持？
- Insist?
坚持什么？我跟你握手？
On what? That I shake your hand?
那恐怕我得坚持与你作对
Oh, then I'm afraid I must insist in the opposite direction.
- 知道我怎么看你？ - 你怎么看我？不知道
- You know what I think you are? - What you think I am? No, I don't.
我看你是输不起
- I think you are a bad loser.
我看你是赢得不光彩
- And I think you're an abysmal winner.
然而
Nevertheless,
在契卡索郡，交易不算完成
here in Chickasaw County, a deal ain't done
除非双方握手
until the two parties have shook hands.
即使签了所有合约也不算
Even after all that paper signin', don't mean shit...
你没跟我握手
you don't shake my hand.
如果我没跟你握手 你会舍弃12000元？
If I don't shake your hand, you're gonna throw away $12,000?
我认为不会
I don't think so.
布奇先生
Mr. Pooch?
这个哈黑鬼的德国人跟我握手前 如果她想离开这里
If she tries to leave here before this nigger-loving German shakes my hand,
你就毙了她
you cut her ass down.
你真想要我跟你握手？
You really want me to shake your hand?
我坚持
I insist.
既然你坚持
If you insist.
不！凯文！
No! Calvin!
凯文！
Calvin!
抱歉，我控制不了
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
黑人抓狂了！救命！
Ni99er's gone crazy! Help!
救命，他杀光所有人
Help, he's killing everyone!
- 老天 - 糟了
Holy...! Shit!
- 王八蛋 - 贱人
Son of a bitch!
可恶，妈的
Damn it! Fuckin'...!
搞屁
Get the...!
可恶，王八蛋，搞啥
Damn it, son of a bitch! What...?
天杀的黑鬼
Fucking...
可恶
Goddamn it!
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck is going on?
你射到我了
You shot me!
你这猪脑袋
- You stupid son of a bitch!
抱歉，杰西
- Sorry, Jessie!
谁居然给黑人枪？
Who the fuck gave a nigger a goddamn gun?
瞄低
Aim low!
黑鬼！我要杀了你！
Nigger! Gonna kill...!
天啊，我的天啊
God! Oh, my God!
混帐东西
Motherfucker!
靠！
Shit!
可恶
Shit.
停火！
Hold your fire!
别开枪了，该死
Stop shootin', goddamn it!
决哥
Django!
什么？
What?
我们抓到你的女人
We got your woman!
比利克莱许的枪顶着她的头
Billy Crash here got his pistol upside her head.
你再不停止屠杀 他会轰了她的头
You don't stop all that carrying on, he gonna blow her goddamn brains out.
这不只是威胁，骑马仔
And that ain't no threat, horse boy.
这是保证
That there is a promise.
或是…
Or...
你能投降，缴械
you can give up, throw your gun out...
我们就不会杀希达
- ...we won't kill Hildi.
狗屁
- Horseshit!
说真的，决哥，我对天发誓
Honest lnjun, Django. I swear 'fore God.
你投降
You give up,
她就不会受到伤害
ain't no harm gonna come to her.
我该相信你这黑鬼吗？
And I'm supposed to believe your black ass?
就我个人，我才不鸟你相不相信
Personally, I don't give a good goddamn what you believe or don't believe!
但我相信你10秒内不投降
I believe if you don't give up in the next ten seconds,
我们会把这女人的头轰掉 你最好相信
we gonna blow this bitch's brains out! Believe that!
不要
Don't do it.
你不要管我
You give me up.
- 6 !    - 别管我
- Six! - Just let me go.
- 7 !  - 他们夺走太多了
- Seven! - They got too much.
- 决哥  - 8 !
- Django. - Eight!
我爱你
- I love you.
9 ! - Nine!
等等
- Hold it!
不要
- No.
我放弃
L give UP-
我听不到，黑鬼
I can't hear you, nigger.
我说我投降
I said I give up!
不要！
No! No!
该醒了，黑鬼
Cock-a-doodle-do, nigger.
你们是赏金猎人，是吧？
So y'all bounty hunters?
我就知道你们很可疑
I knew there was something fishy about y'all.
我们在你们的鞍囊中
We found your wanted posters...
发现通缉令和帐簿
and book of figures in your saddlebags.
我得说
I got to say...
我之前从没听过黑人的赏金猎人
I ain't never heard of no black bounty hunter before.
黑人收钱杀白人？这啥台词啊
Black boy paid to kill white men? How'd you like that line of work?
可能是冷笑话吧
Probably pretty good while it lasted,
该跟你的蛋蛋道晚安了，黑仔 数到3 1
Time to say good night to them nuts, blackie. On three. One...
别乱动，2
l I got you. Two...
冷静，好戏要登场了
Calm down, now, here it comes.
领班
" Captain?"
拉拉小姐要见你
Miss Lara want to see you.
要讨论主人的葬礼事宜
Something to do with the Old Man's funeral.
她改变主意不阉决哥了
Oh, and she changed her mind 'bout snipping Django.
她要把他交给雷昆迪基的人
She gonna give him to the LeQuint Dickey people.
她讲得这么临时
Well, she didn't waste a minute telling me.
令人大失所望
How disappointing.
你要走了
You leavin'.
你能带走这些
This here what you take with you.
你这黑鬼的事迹让主屋那群人…
Your black ass has been all them motherfuckers at The Big House
议论纷纷好几小时
could talk about for the last few hours.
好像白人这辈子只会把头脑用在…
Seem like white folk ain't never had a bright idea in they life
想出杀你的各种方法
was coming up with all kinds of ways to kill your ass.
提醒你 多数点子都跟乱搞你的小弟弟有关
Now, mind you, most of them ideas had to do with fuckin' with your fun parts.
那似乎是个好点子
Now, that may seem like a good idea,
但实际上
but truth is...
当黑人被阉了
when you snip a nigger's nuts,
多数人会在7分钟内流血至死
most of them bleed out in, oh, about, hm... seven minutes.
多数人
Most of 'em.
绝大多数
Well, more than most.
然后我说
Then I says:
“屁啦”
"Shitfire."
“我们卖给雷昆迪基的黑人比那更惨”
The niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey got it worse than that."
他们继续说“把他鞭死”
And they still sayin', "Let's whip him to death."
“把他丢进曼丁果格斗 把他喂史东赛佛的狗”
Or "Throw him to the Mandingos." "Feed him to Stonesipher's dogs."
我说“那又什么特别”
And I said, "What's so special about that?"
“我们经常那样搞”
We do that shit all the time.
“那敢情好”
"Hell's bells,
“我们卖给雷昆迪基的黑人比那更惨”
the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey got it worse than that."
阿娘喂
Lo and behold,
突然拉拉小姐想出一个妙计
out of nowhere, Miss Lara come up with the bright idea
把你交给雷昆迪基矿业公司
of giving your ass to the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company.
作为雷昆迪基矿业公司的奴隶
And as a slave of the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company,
今后，直到你吗屁那天
henceforth, till the day you die,
整天，每天
all day, every day,
你会挥着大锤
you will be swinging a sledgehammer,
把大石头敲成小石子
turning big rocks into little rocks.
你到了那里
Now, when you get there,
他们会夺去你的名字
they gonna take away your name,
给你一个编号和大锤
give you a number and a sledgehammer,
对你喊“干活了”
and say, "Get to work!"
一反嘴，舌头说被割掉
One word of sass, they cuts out your tongue.
他们也很拿手，你不会流血至死
And they good at it too. You won't bleed out.
真的很拿手
They does that real good.
他们会操死你
They gonna work ya.
整天，每天，直到你再也不行
All day, every day, till your back give out.
他们就会用榔头砸你的头
Then they're gonna hit you in the head with a hammer,
把你丢到黑鬼洞
throw your ass down the nigger hole.
这就是你的一生，决哥
And that will be the story of you, Django.
（往雷昆迪基矿业公司的途中）
法兰基，指导原则是什么？
And what's the golden rule, Frankie?
不跟土著打炮
You don't root abos.
白人小子
Hey, white boy.
我在叫你，白人小子
I said, hey, white boy.
闭嘴，黑人 我对你想说的话兴趣缺缺
Shut up, black. You ain't got nothing to say I want to hear.
你想赚11000元吗？
How'd you like to make $11,000?
你在说啥？
Do what, now?
我说你想赚11000元吗？
I said how'd you like to make $11,000?
- 其实是11500元 - 你在说什么鬼？
11,500, actually. What the fuck are you talking about?
在刚才的糖果园庄园 有11500元的巨款
Back there at that plantation, Candyland, there was an $11,500 fortune,
就摆在那里，你们都错过了
just sittin' there. And y'all rode right past it.
去你的，黑仔，我们不是强盗
You be damned, blackie, we're not bandits.
没叫你抢 这笔巨款的好处就是不违法
I ain't saying that. Nice thing about this fortune is it ain't illegal.
不能用偷的 要用挣的，白人小子
You can't steal it. You got to earn it, white boy.
有话快说，有屁快放
You got something to say, mate, you say it.
11500元巨款在糖果园等你
The $11,500 fortune waitin' for you back at Candyland
形式就是史密提毕考帮…
is in the form of a "Wanted Dead or Alive" bounty
- “无论生死通缉令”的赏金 - 史密提毕考是什么人？
on Smitty Bacall and the Bacall Gang. Who the fuck is Smitty Bacall?
史密提毕考是火车劫杀帮派 史密提毕考帮的头目
Smitty Bacall is the leader of this murderous gang of stagecoach robbers, the Bacall Gang.
杀了他有7000元赏金
There's a $7,000 "Wanted Dead or Alive" bounty on him,
他的三个共犯每个1500元
$1,500 for each of his three accomplices:
丹尼麦可斯
Dandy Michaels,
杰拉德纳许和疯子克雷格库恩
Gerald Nash, and Crazy Craig Koons.
他们全部四人
Now, all four of them gentlemen,
正在糖果园里狂笑，知道原因？
they back there at Candyland laughing their ass off.
因为他们逃过谋杀罪了 但他们不会得逞
You know why? 'Cause they just got away with murder. But it ain't got to be that way.
你和你同伴 你们能回去挣那笔钱
You and your mates, y'all can ride back there and y'all can go get that money.
- 你说这些败类干了什么？ - 这些王八蛋滥杀无辜
What'd these jokers do again? These sons of bitches, they killed innocent people.
马车抢劫，杀无辜白人
Stagecoach robbery. Innocent white people.
我的口袋里有传单，能拿给你
I got the handbill right here in my pocket, if you let me get it.
拿出来
Get it out.
“通缉，无论生死 史密提毕考…”
"Wanted. Dead or alive. Smitty Bacall
- “和史密提毕考同伙” - 但你是奴隶
and the Smitty Bacall Gang." - But you're a slave.
- “因谋杀…” - 我才不是奴隶
- "For murder..." - I ain't no goddamn slave.
“和马车抢劫”
- "...and stagecoach robbery."
我的口气像奴隶吗？
Do I sound like a fuckin' slave?
- “7000元悬赏史密提毕考” - 一大笔钱耶
"$7,000 for Smitty Bacall." - That's a shitload.
我是赏金猎人
- I'm a bounty hunter.
昨天，我是自由民
Yesterday, as a free man,
我与我的德国白人伙伴 骑马来到糖果园
I rode into Candyland on a horse with my German white partner,
金史华兹医生
Dr. King Schultz.
我们从德州一路追踪 史密提毕考帮到契卡索郡
We tracked the Bacall Gang all the way from Texas to Chickasaw County.
终于发现他们躲在糖果园
We finally found their ass layin' low in Candyland.
我们进去抓他们，但情况生变
We went in there to get 'em, things went sour,
我的伙伴被杀，凯文康迪中弹
my partner got killed, Calvin Candie got shot,
全庄园的人决定要怪罪我
then everybody there decided to blame me,
我就沦落这地步
so here I am.
但我不该在运送名单上
But y'all know I ain't on that manifest.
我不该被拖上这趟旅途
And all y'all know I ain't supposed to be on this trip.
但他们四人仍在那里，仍受通缉
But them four men is still back there, they're still wanted,
那是唾手可得的11500元
and that 11,500 is up for grabs, and the last thing they'd expect
他们打死料不到你们这记回马枪
is y'all ridin' back in there and gettin' it.
你在盘算什么？
What's the deal?
你供出他们是谁，我们放你走？
You tell us who they are and we turn you loose?
不，我不会供出他们是谁
No, no, no, no. I ain't gonna tell you who they are.
除非你给我一把枪、一匹马
But, you give me a pistol, one of them horses,
还有11500元分我500元 我就会指出他们
and $500 of that 11,500, and I'll point 'em out to you.
这是如假包换的传单
This is a real handbill.
就算传单是真的 不代表他没在胡说
Now just 'cause it's a real handbill doesn't mean that other bunch of malarkey is.
为什么奴隶口袋里会有…
Now why would a slave have a
“无论生死通缉令”传单？
"Wanted Dead or Alive" handbill in his pocket?
那个黑人昨天骑进糖果园？
Did that black ride into Candyland yesterday?
好，我再问你们一次
All right, I'm gonna ask you again.
切记，我不喜欢有人说谎
I want you to remember, I don't like liars.
他是糖果园的奴隶
Is he a Candyland slave,
还是他昨天跟个白人骑马来？
or did he ride in with a white man on a horse yesterday?
对
Yeah.
他们从格林维尔拍卖会就随行
They walked us from the Greenville auction,
他跟个白人骑马来
and he rode in on a horse with a white man.
这个黑人是那白人的奴隶吗？
Now this white man, was the black his slave?
他不是奴隶
He weren't no slave.
你百分之百确定？
- You fuckin' sure about that?
打包票
- Damn sure.
糖果园发生什么事？
- What happened over in Candyland?
大火拼，主人中弹
- Bunch-a shootin'. Massa got shot.
- 谁射杀他？ - 德国人
- Who shot him? - The German.
他为何杀他？
Why'd he do that?
黑人和德国人装成奴隶商 但他们不是
Nigger and the German was actin' like they were slavers but they wasn't.
- 他们是什么？ - 赏金猎人
- Well, what were they? - Bounty hunters.
我靠，罗伊，这可大条了
Fuck me, Roy. I mean, this could be big, mate.
黑人，成交
Well, smoke, you got a deal.
我还有个条件
- I got one more condition.
说吧
- What's that?
我们到那里时，时机来临时
When we get there, when time come...
让我帮你们杀了他
- ...you let me help you kill 'em. - Hey...
真有你的
you're a funny bugger.
- 松开他 - 好
- Cut him loose. - Yeah, yeah.
一言为定，黑人
You got yourself a deal, blackie.
一言为定，伙伴
You got yourself a deal, mate.
喂
Hey!
以黑人来说你挺不赖的
You're all right for a black fella. Oh, yeah.
好了，伙伴
There we go. There you go, mate.
好
Yeah.
那边的驮马给你
We're gonna give you that packhorse over there.
- 鞍囊里装什么？ - 炸药
What them saddlebags got in 'em?
免谈，我才不骑背着炸药的马
- Dynamite. - No. I ain't ridin' no horse with no goddamn dynamite on its back.
我能理解
I can understand that.
法兰基，让马卸下炸药棒
Frankie, why don't you take them sticks off that horse
插在黑鬼笼子上
and stick 'em in the nigger cage.
来点炸药给你们黑鬼乐一下
A little dynamite for you black fellas to play with.
佛洛伊，马车上有枪吧？
Now, Floyd, you got that rifle up on the wagon, don't ya?
对
Yeah, right.
把你的枪和枪套给他
Why don't you give him your gun and gun belt?
好
Righto.
别摔到那玩意，好吗？
Now, don't drop the fuckin' thing, all right?
我刚修好瞄准器，准得很
I've just had the sights fixed and they're perfect.
多谢告知
Oh, that's good to know.
把炸药丢给我
Throw me up that dynamite.
- 杰克 - 什么事？
- Jake! - Yeah?
快去看狗在鬼叫什么
Get out there and see what's wrong with them goddamn dogs!
干掉他们
Kill them
杀了达太安，烂胚子
D'Artagnan, motherfuckers!
Hey!
(12000元，凯文康迪）
（布希达冯夏夫）
再会了
Auf Wiedersehen.
是我，宝贝
It's me, baby.
到那日，乐无比
In the sweet By-and-by
我们会相聚
We will meet
在那美丽的岸边
On that beautiful shore
到那日 到那日
By-and-by By-and-by
到那日 乐无比
By-and-by We will meet
到那日，我们会相聚
- We will meet by-and-by - Cora?
柯拉，替大家准备一些咖啡
Would you prepare us some coffee?
夏芭，你帮她
Sheba, you help her.
来吧
Come on.
乐无比
In the sweet
到那日
By-and-by
你们到那日都会跟凯文相聚
Oh, y'all gonna be together with Calvin in the by-and-by, all right.
只是比你们想像还早一点
Just a bit sooner than y'all was expectin'.
比利克莱许，我们进行到哪里？
Billy Crash. Now, where were we?
想到了
Oh, that's right.
上次见到你，你用脏手碰我那里
Last time I seen you, you had your hands on my...
我的妈呀
瘸哥，你这王八黑鬼
Django! You black son of a bitch!
是决哥，识相点
The D is silent, hillbilly.
不要！
Oh, no!
你们这些黑人
Now, all you black folks,
建议你们远离这些白人
I suggest you get away from all these white folks.
你不行，史提芬
Not you, Stephen.
你给我留下
You right where you belong.
柯拉，你走之前 向拉拉小姐道别好吗？
Cora, before you go, will you tell Miss Lara goodbye?
什么？
- Do what now?
我说“向拉拉小姐道别”
- I said, "Tell Miss Lara goodbye."
再见，拉拉小姐
Bye, Miss Lara.
你们两个能闪人了
Y'all two run along now.
史提芬，喜欢我这身新衣吗？
Stephen, how you like my new duds?
之前我不晓得血红色跟我很搭
You know, before now I didn't know that burgundy was my color.
我数了发射六枪，黑人
I count six shots, nigger.
我数有两支枪，黑人
I count two guns, nigger.
你说76年来在这座庄园
You said in 76 years on this plantation,
你看过残害黑人的各种恶行
you seen all manner-a shit done to niggers.
但我发现，你没提到击穿膝盖
But I notice, you didn't mention kneecappin'.
天啊！混蛋！可恶！
Oh, God! Motherfucker! Damn it!
76年，史提芬
Seventy-six years, Stephen.
你看过多少黑人来来去去？ 7000个？
How many niggers you think you see come and go? Seven thousand?
8000个？
Eight thousand?
9000个？
Nine thousand?
9999个？
Nine thousand, nine hundred and ninety-nine?
凯文康迪嘴里吐出的每个字 全是狗屁倒灶
Every single word that came out of Calvin Candie's mouth was nothin'
但他说对一件事 我是万中选一的黑人
but horseshit. I am that one nigger in 10,000.
你这王八蛋
You son of a bitch!
你这狗杂碎
You motherfucker!
老天爷，让我杀了这黑人
Oh, sweet Jesus, let me kill this nigger!
你不会全身而退的，决哥
You ain't gonna get away with this, Django!
他们会逮捕你
They gonna catch your black ass.
你会出现在通缉令上
You gonna be on the wanted posters now, nigger.
赏金猎人会追杀你
The bounty hunters gonna be lookin' for you.
你能逃走，但他们一定会揪出你
You can run, nigger, but they gonna find your ass!
到时候，天啊，看他们怎么搞你
And when they do, oh, Lord, what they gonna do to your ass!
他们不会轻易杀了你，你完蛋了
They ain't gonna just kill you, nigger! You done fucked up!
这座糖果园，黑人！ 你毁不了糖果园！
This Candyland, nigger! You can't destroy Candyland!
我们就在这里，永远都有糖果园！
We been here! There's always gonna be a Candyland!
没有黑人枪手能杀光全世界的白人
Can't no nigger gunfighter kill all the white folks in the world!
他们会揪出你
They gonna find your black ass!
决哥
Django!
你这妄自尊大的…
You uppity son of a...
嗨，小麻烦
Hey, Little Trouble Maker.
嗨，大麻烦
Hey, Big Trouble Maker.
知道江湖上会怎么称你？
You know what they are going to call you?
“南方第一快枪”
"The fastest gun in the South."
我们走吧
Let's get outta here.
那个黑人是何方神圣？
Who was that nigger?